[
    [
        {
            "category": "Visual Arts",
            "question": "Born in Crete, this influential painter moved to Spain, where he became highly sought-after for his religious works. His paintings are characterized by elongated figures, dramatic lighting, and an intense spirituality that reflects the religious fervor of his time. Name this artist that was nicknamed for his nationality and is considered a significant figure in the Spanish Renaissance.",
            "answers": ["El Greco", "Dominikos Theotokopoulos"]
        },
        {
            "num": 21,
            "category": "Literature",
            "subcategory": "American",
            "difficulty": "MS",
            "tournament": "Collaborative MS Tournament",
            "question": "This city is where Ralph Ellison's Invisible Man works at the Liberty Paint Company. George Selden wrote about a cricket in one of this city's major public spaces. The Great Gatsby takes place in this city where Percy Jackson visits the Metropolitan Museum of Art. This city is where Stuart Little races boats in Central Park. Name this city in which the Harlem Renaissance took place.",
            "round": "1",
            "year": 2012,
            "answers": ["New York City"],
            "id": 391
        },
        {
            "num": 10,
            "category": "Science",
            "subcategory": null,
            "difficulty": "MS",
            "tournament": "Collaborative MS Tournament",
            "question": "pH in this fluid is regulated by the bicarbonate ion buffer system. Cells in this fluid include leukocytes and erythrocytes, while platelets help form clots that stop its flow. It is carried in arteries and veins. Name this fluid that delivers oxygen and nutrients to cells and is pumped by the heart.",
            "round": "CMST_Round08.pdf",
            "year": 2010,
            "answers": ["blood"],
            "id": 576
        },
        {
            "num": 7,
            "category": "Science",
            "subcategory": "Other",
            "difficulty": "MS",
            "tournament": "Collaborative MS Tournament",
            "question": "Starburst types of these systems have unusually high supplies of gas, and they can combine in a process known as cannibalism. The \"tuning fork diagram\" is a graphic depiction of the Hubble classification scheme for these systems, which divides them into irregular, elliptical and spiral types. M31 is the Andromeda one. Name these regions of the universe that include the Milky Way.",
            "round": "1",
            "year": 2011,
            "answers": ["galaxies", "galaxy"],
            "id": 294
        },
        {
            "num": 10,
            "category": "Geography",
            "subcategory": "Norse",
            "difficulty": "MS",
            "tournament": "Collaborative MS Tournament",
            "question": "This country was officially recognized in the Lateran Treaties of 1929. It has extraterritorial authority over Castel Gandolfo. Places of interest in this country include the Sistine Chapel and Saint Peter's Square and Basilica. Voting in this country is restricted to Cardinals under eighty years old. Name this world's smallest country located entirely within the city of Rome.",
            "round": "4",
            "year": 2012,
            "answers": [
                "State of the Vatican City",
                "Holy See",
                "Santa Sede",
                "Stato della Citta del Vaticano"
            ],
            "id": 406
        },
        {
            "question": "An American writer known for his macabre and mysterious stories, his haunting prose and explorations of themes like madness and guilt established him as a master of Gothic literature. Name this author who gained recognition with his poem 'The Raven'.",
            "answers": ["Edgar Allan Poe", "Poe"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "id": 80
        },
        {
            "num": 11,
            "category": "Literature",
            "subcategory": "American",
            "difficulty": "MS",
            "tournament": "Collaborative MS Tournament",
            "question": "This poet delivered \"The Gift Outright\" at President John F. Kennedy's inauguration. One of his poems observes that \"good fences make good neighbors\" and is called \"Mending Wall.\" His poem \"Nothing Gold Can Stay\" notes that \"Nature's first green is gold.\" Name this poet who stated in his most famous poem that he took \"the road less traveled by, and that has made all the difference.\"",
            "round": "6",
            "year": 2012,
            "answers": ["Robert Lee Frost"],
            "id": 752
        },
        {
            "num": 15,
            "category": "Mythology",
            "subcategory": null,
            "difficulty": "MS",
            "tournament": "Collaborative MS Tournament",
            "question": "This figure met his demise when he was struck by a piece of wood from his own vessel. While in Colchis visiting King Aeetes, he accomplished such tasks as yoking fire-breathing oxen and dispatching a group of warriors that sprang forth after dragon teeth were sown into the ground, all to get the Golden Fleece. He was aided in these tasks by his future wife Medea. Name this leader of the Argonauts.",
            "round": "CMST_Round09.pdf",
            "year": 2010,
            "answers": ["Jason"],
            "id": 214
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This video game series is set in a post-apocalyptic world that features a retro-futuristic setting influenced by the post-war culture of 1950s America, imagining an alternate history where the transistor was never invented. Known for its open-world gameplay, it allows players to explore vast wastelands and make choices that affect the game's story and environment. Developed by Bethesda Game Studios and recently adapted into a TV show, what is the name of this RPG series that begins with the aftermath of a global nuclear war?",
            "answers": ["Fallout"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This treaty's Article 231, known as the \"War Guilt Clause,\" assigned full blame for the war and all damages to Germany and its allies. It not only demanded reparations and territory from Germany but also mandated the disarmament of the German military and limited the size of the German navy. Additionally, it led to the creation of new nations in Eastern Europe and the League of Nations. What is the name of this treaty, that was signed in the Hall of Mirrors in a palace and ended World War I?",
            "answers": ["Treaty of Versailles"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Before basketball, this athlete was a competitive swimmer, aiming to compete in the Olympics. Known for his calm demeanor and fundamental playing style, he earned the nickname \"The Big Fundamental.\" He played his entire 19-season NBA career with the San Antonio Spurs, winning five NBA championships and two MVP awards. Who is this legendary power forward, celebrated for his leadership and consistency on the court?",
            "answers": ["Tim Duncan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This famous American traitor started his military career as a pharmacist and bookseller. He initially became a hero in the early stages of the American Revolutionary War by playing a key role in the capture of Fort Ticonderoga and was pivotal in the Battle of Saratoga. However, his name became synonymous with treason after his plot to surrender West Point to the British was exposed. He later served as a brigadier general in the British Army. Who is this controversial figure in American history?",
            "answers": ["Benedict Arnold"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This series is noted for its complex characters and storylines, as well as its frequent use of shocking plot twists, including the infamous \"Red Wedding\" episode. It is based on the book series \"A Song of Ice and Fire\" by George R.R. Martin, who served as a producer on the show. The show's extensive filming locations included Northern Ireland, Croatia, Iceland, and Spain. It set a record for the most Emmy Awards won by a scripted television series. What is the name of this fantasy television series that follows the power struggles among the Seven Kingdoms of Westeros?",
            "answers": ["\"Game of Thrones\""],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This vast desert is not only composed of sand dunes; it also features mountains, rock plateaus, and extensive gravel plains. It is home to the desert ant, Cataglyphis bicolor, known for its unique ability to withstand extreme temperatures by sprinting across the sand. Despite its arid climate, it houses over 20 lakes, most of which are saltwater lakes. Covering most of North Africa, it is nearly as large as the United States. What is the name of this desert, the largest hot desert in the world?",
            "answers": ["Sahara Desert"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Formulated in 1925, this equation is a key foundation of quantum mechanics and provides a mathematical description of the wave-like behavior of particles at atomic and subatomic scales. Unlike classical mechanics, it uses a wave function to describe probabilistically the state of a particle rather than determining precise outcomes. Developed by an Austrian physicist who later won the Nobel Prize in Physics in 1933 for his contributions to the wave theory of matter, this equation has revolutionized our understanding of the atomic world. What is the name of this critical equation in quantum physics?",
            "answers": ["Schrodinger's Equation"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This ancient epic is traditionally attributed to a poet who is also credited with composing another foundational work of ancient Greek literature that details a famous war. The narrative centers on the protagonist's challenging journey home following the fall of Troy, which takes an arduous ten years to complete. Throughout his voyage, he encounters various mythical creatures including the Cyclops, the seductive Sirens, and the shape-shifting witch-goddess Circe. This epic is not just a tale of adventure but also explores themes of heroism, loyalty, and the human condition. What is the name of this seminal work, a cornerstone of ancient Greek literature, detailing the adventures of Odysseus?",
            "answers": ["The Odyssey"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Before entering politics, this future president briefly ran a general store and served as a Captain for the Illinois Miltia during the Black Hawk War. Despite his iconic image, he is the only president to hold a patent for an invention. His stovepipe hat was a practical accessory meant to hold important documents and letters. Name this president known for his leadership during the Civil War.",
            "answers": ["Abraham Lincoln"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Major League Baseball team was originally founded in Baltimore, Maryland, in 1901 before moving to New York City in 1903. Known for their distinctive pinstripe uniforms, they are often referred to by their nickname, \"The Bronx Bombers.\" The team holds the record for the most MLB championships, having won 27 World Series titles. Their storied rivalries, especially with the Boston Red Sox, are among the most famous in baseball history. What is the name of this iconic baseball team, synonymous with success and a global fanbase?",
            "answers": ["New York Yankees", "Yankees"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This play is set in the Kingdom of Denmark and features a plot that revolves around themes of treachery, revenge, incest, and moral corruption. The protagonist of the play studies in Wittenberg and is visited by the ghost of his father, who reveals the truth about his murder. Famous for its exploration of the human psyche, it introduces phrases like \"To be, or not to be\" into the English lexicon. Name this tragedy, often considered William Shakespeare's masterpiece, which centers on the Prince of Denmark.",
            "answers": ["\"Hamlet\"", "Hamlet"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Launched into low Earth orbit in 1990, this space-based observatory has become one of the most important instruments in the history of astronomy. It was not the first space telescope, but it is one of the largest and most versatile, known for its deep field images that have provided a deeper look into space and time. This telescope is named after an American astronomer who is famous for his discovery of the universe's expansion. What is the name of this telescope that has allowed astronomers to observe the most distant stars and galaxies ever seen",
            "answers": ["Hubble Space Telescope"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This ancient trade route played a critical role in the spread of Buddhism from India to East Asia. It was established during the Han Dynasty around 130 B.C, and famous travelers like Marco Polo and Ibn Battuta traversed the route, documenting their journeys. Name this historic trade route which connected China with the Mediterranean.",
            "answers": ["The Silk Road"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This peak experiences geological uplift, growing approximately 4 mm every year. Its \"death zone\" above 8,000 meters is notorious for its harsh conditions, where the thin air contains insufficient oxygen to sustain human life for extended periods, contributing to the peril many climbers face. Successfully ascended for the first time by Sir Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay in 1953, this mountain is renowned globally. What is the name of this mountain, known as the highest point on Earth?",
            "answers": ["Mount Everest"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This actress made her stage debut in the play \"The Playboy of Seville\" in 1971. She is known for her ability to master almost any accent, from a British accent in \"The Iron Lady\" to a Polish one in \"Sophie's Choice.\" She holds the record for the most Academy Award nominations of any actor. Known for her roles in diverse films from \"Kramer vs. Kramer\" to \"The Devil Wears Prada,\" who is this acclaimed actress often described as the \"best actress of her generation\"?",
            "answers": ["Meryl Streep"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This golf tournament is the only major that does not rotate between courses, being held annually at the same location since its inception in 1934. It is known for its green jacket, which is awarded to the champion and must be returned to the clubhouse after a year. The event was won by Scottie Scheffler in 2024 and 2022 which Jon Rahm winning in between. Held in Augusta, Georgia, what is the name of this prestigious golf tournament, one of the four major championships in professional golf?",
            "answers": ["The Masters"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This American virologist was born in New York City in 1914. After focusing on influenza research, he shifted his attention to a viral disease that caused widespread fear and paralysis, particularly affecting children. In a significant act of public service, he chose not to patent his greatest medical discovery, famously stating, \"Could you patent the sun?\" His research led to the first effective vaccine against polio, introduced in 1955. What is the name of this influential medical researcher?",
            "answers": ["Jonas Salk"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This international competition features a trophy made of 18-carat gold and weighs approximately 6 kilograms. The inaugural tournament was held in 1930, hosted by Uruguay, who also won the title. It is the most watched sporting event globally, surpassing even the Olympic Games in viewership. Held every four years, teams from around the world compete, but only Brazil has won five times, the most by any country. What is the name of this prestigious international football tournament?",
            "answers": ["FIFA World Cup", "world cup"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This ruler of the Mali Empire during the early 14th century is celebrated not only for his wealth but also for his contributions to the spread of Islam in West Africa. He embarked on a famous pilgrimage to Mecca in 1324, which included a procession of thousands of attendants and camels laden with gold. His journey through Cairo was notably extravagant, causing a temporary devaluation of gold in the region due to his generous distributions. Under his reign, the legendary city of Timbuktu flourished as a center of trade and Islamic scholarship, marked by the construction of the Djinguereber Mosque. Who is this emperor, often cited as one of the wealthiest people in history?",
            "answers": ["Mansa Musa"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This marine structure is large enough to be visible from space, comprising over 2,900 individual reefs and 900 islands. It hosts a significant population of dugongs and is one of the most biodiverse ecosystems on the planet. The reef is a breeding area for humpback whales migrating from the Antarctic. Located off the coast of Queensland in northeastern Australia, it is the world's largest coral reef system. What is the name of this UNESCO World Heritage Site known for its vibrant marine life?",
            "answers": ["Great Barrier Reef"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This artist served in the First Regiment of African Light Cavalry in Algeria for two years. He suffered from cataracts in his later years, which greatly influenced his shift to broader brushstrokes and bolder color choices in his paintings. He is known for his detailed garden at Giverny, which he transformed into a living canvas and used as inspiration for many works. His series on water lilies and scenes of the French countryside are celebrated globally. Name this French painter, a founding father of Impressionism.",
            "answers": ["Claude Monet"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Constructed between 1792 and 1800, this iconic building was designed by Irish-born architect James Hoban. It has 132 rooms, 35 bathrooms, and 6 levels in the residence. It was rebuilt after being burned down during the War of 1812 in an event known as the Burning of Washington. Its first resident was President John Adams. What is this famous building called?",
            "answers": ["White House"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This novel intricately portrays the clash of cultures between feudal Japan and the Western world during the early 17th century. It is based on the historical adventures of an English navigator who becomes a samurai and political player within the Japanese feudal system. Published in 1975, it became a bestseller and was later adapted into a successful television miniseries in 1980 and again in 2024. What is the name of this historical novel by James Clavell that explores the rise of a foreigner in the Japanese samurai-led society?",
            "answers": ["Shogun"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This actor began his career with appearances in television commercials before moving on to recurring roles in TV series such as \"Growing Pains.\" He is a committed environmentalist, founding a non-profit organization focused on global warming and preserving Earth's biodiversity. He received critical acclaim for his performance in \"What's Eating Gilbert Grape\" at a young age. Known for his collaborations with director Martin Scorsese in films like \"The Wolf of Wall Street\" and \"Shutter Island,\" who is this Oscar-winning actor famous for his role in \"Titanic\"?",
            "answers": ["Leonardo DiCaprio"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Constructed over several dynasties, this extensive fortification stretches more than 13,000 miles and was primarily built using tamped earth and later enhanced with brick and stone. Its construction began as early as the 7th century BC, with significant extensions during the Ming Dynasty. Originally designed to protect against nomadic invasions, it also controlled immigration and facilitated duties on goods transported along the Silk Road. What is this historical landmark?",
            "answers": ["The Great Wall of China", "great wall"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Initially derived from the pancreases of dogs and later from cattle and pigs, this hormone plays a critical role in part of the body's metabolic regulation. Its first use in treating a human patient was in 1922. This medical advancement earned the discovering scientist the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine in 1923. Today, it is synthesized using recombinant DNA technology, providing essential treatment for diabetes patients worldwide. What is this life-saving hormone called?",
            "answers": ["Insulin"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This ancient lake contains over 20% of the world's unfrozen freshwater reserve. It earned the nickname \"Gal\u00e1pagos of Russia\" due to its unique biodiversity. It is home to the world's only freshwater seal species. This UNESCO World Heritage Site boasts an exceptional array of endemic species. Located in southern Siberia, it is the world's deepest lake. What is the name of this lake, often referred to as the 'Pearl of Siberia'?",
            "answers": ["Lake Baikal"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Before his infamous legal battles, this individual had a successful career in advertising, notably appearing in commercials for the Hertz rental car company. He set records in the NFL, including rushing over 2,000 yards in a single season, a feat achieved during a 14-game season. His transition to film and television included roles in movies and the popular \"Naked Gun\" series. In 1994, he was tried and acquitted in a highly publicized and controversial criminal trial for the murders of his ex-wife Nicole Brown Simpson and her friend Ronald Goldman. Who is this infamous former NFL running back and actor who died in 2024?",
            "answers": ["O.J. Simpson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This competition is one of the most grueling one-day sporting events in the world, combining three continuous and sequential endurance races. It starts with a 2.4-mile swim, followed by a 112-mile bicycle ride, and finishes with a marathon 26.2-mile run, raced in that order without a break. Originating in Hawaii in 1978 as a challenge among groups of athletes to see who was the fittest\u2014swimmers, cyclists, or runners\u2014it has grown into a global phenomenon. What is the name of this triathlon that tests the limits of human endurance?",
            "answers": ["Ironman", "Ironman Triathlon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This film features a famous scene with a severed horse's head, which was real and acquired from a dog food company. The hauntingly beautiful score for the film was composed by Nino Rota. It is based on a novel by Mario Puzo and portrays the powerful Italian-American crime family of Don Vito Corleone. The film launched the careers of several actors, including Al Pacino, who plays Michael Corleone. Directed by Francis Ford Coppola, what is the name of this iconic film that won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1972?",
            "answers": ["\"The Godfather\"", "Godfather"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This historic chapel's ceiling was originally painted blue and decorated with stars before being replaced by the artwork that is seen today. It serves as the site for the Papal conclave, where new popes are elected. Renowned for its Renaissance art, particularly the frescoes that cover the interior, it features works by several prominent artists of the period, including Botticelli, Perugino, and Michelangelo. Michelangelo's contributions include not only the ceiling but also the iconic \"The Last Judgment\" on the altar wall. What is the name of this chapel located in Vatican City, famous for its magnificent Renaissance art?",
            "answers": ["The Sistine Chapel"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Before joining NASA, this astronaut flew 78 combat missions during the Korean War and tested high-speed aircraft, including the X-15. He was part of the Gemini 8 mission, achieving the first successful docking of two spacecraft in orbit. He later became the first person to walk on the moon, famously declaring, \"That's one small step for [a] man, one giant leap for mankind.\" Who is this pioneering astronaut?",
            "answers": ["Neil Armstrong"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This painting was created during the artist's time at the Saint-Paul-de-Mausole asylum in Saint-R\u00e9my-de-Provence, France, after he voluntarily admitted himself. It depicts the view from the east-facing window of his asylum room, though it was painted from memory during the day. Characterized by swirling clouds in a starry night and a bright crescent moon, its vibrant colors and emotional depth are a signature of the artist's turbulent state of mind. Currently housed in the Museum of Modern Art in New York City, this work is one of the most recognized paintings in the history of Western culture. Name this iconic 1889 painting by Vincent van Gogh.",
            "answers": ["The Starry Night"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This television series was pitched by its creator, Vince Gilligan, as a story where the protagonist transforms into the antagonist. It features a character named Saul Goodman, who was later the subject of a successful spin-off prequel series. Filmed primarily in Albuquerque, New Mexico, it uses the unique landscape as a backdrop to its intense narrative. The series centers on Walter White, a high school chemistry teacher turned methamphetamine manufacturer. What is the name of this critically acclaimed series that won multiple Emmy Awards for its lead actor, Bryan Cranston?",
            "answers": ["\"Breaking Bad\"", "Breaking Bad"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This South American river is home to the uniquely colored and intelligent pink river dolphin. It flows through the world's largest tropical rainforest, encompassing an area twice the size of India. Despite its vast length, it has no bridges due to its width and the dense forest surrounding much of its length. It is the second-longest river globally but discharges the largest volume of water, influencing the Atlantic Ocean up to 100 miles from its mouth. What is the name of this river?",
            "answers": ["Amazon River"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Originally built between 1871 and 1888 to accommodate the growing staff of the White House, this French Second Empire-style building is located next to the West Wing. It was initially known as the State, War, and Navy Building, reflecting its original occupants. Since 2002, its name honor has honored the 34th U.S. President. What is the official name of this building where the Vice President has an office?",
            "answers": [
                "Eisenhower Executive Office Building",
                "EEOB",
                "Eisenhower"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "First isolated using simple adhesive tape, this material was discovered at the University of Manchester by Andre Geim and Konstantin Novoselov, who were later awarded the Nobel Prize in Physics in 2010 for their work. It is notable for being just one atom thick, making it one of the thinnest yet strongest materials ever tested.What is this two-dimensional material composed of a single layer of carbon atoms arranged in a honeycomb lattice?",
            "answers": ["Graphene"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This athlete has a successful fashion line and has also been involved in numerous off-court ventures, including voice acting in animated films. She won her first major championship at the U.S. Open in 1999, setting the stage for one of the most dominant careers in tennis. Known for her powerful playing style and strong serve, she has won 23 Grand Slam singles titles, the most by any player in the Open Era. Who is this iconic tennis player, often celebrated as one of the greatest athletes of all time?",
            "answers": ["Serena Williams"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This period saw the development of the printing press by Johannes Gutenberg, significantly impacting the accessibility of knowledge. Notably, it emphasized humanism, redefining the intellectual landscape of Europe.It heralded major advancements in arts, introducing techniques like perspective in painting, represented by masters such as Leonardo da Vinci and Michelangelo. Name this cultural phenomenon that began in 14th century Florence and was characterized by a revival of classical learning and wisdom, a shift that distanced Europe from the Middle Ages.",
            "answers": ["The Renaissance"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This country is home to one of the world's oldest continuous major civilizations, with historical and urban settlements dating back to 4000 BC. It was known as Persia until 1935 and has a significant role in the history of the silk road and international trade. The nation is also known for its substantial oil reserves, ranking as the world's fourth-largest holder of oil. It features a diverse landscape ranging from arid mountains to lush forests. What is the name of this country that launched an air attack at Israel after they destroyed it's embassy in Syria?",
            "answers": ["Iran"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This historical figure was born an Archduchess of Austria before becoming the Queen of France through her marriage to Louis XVI. Known for her extravagant lifestyle amid France's financial crisis, she was a controversial queen, often misquoted in response to hearing that the French peasants had no bread. Her reputation, whether deserved or not, fueled populist rage that contributed to the climactic moments of the French Revolution. She met her end by guillotine in 1793 during the Reign of Terror. Who is this queen, often remembered for her dramatic downfall?",
            "answers": ["Marie Antoinette"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Developed by a French mathematician in the early 19th century, this mathematical transform is essential for analyzing the frequencies contained in a signal. It decomposes a function or a dataset into a spectrum of its sine and cosine components, enabling engineers and scientists to work with the frequency domain rather than time domain. This technique has wide-ranging applications, including image processing, signal analysis, and quantum physics. What is the name of this transformative analysis method, named after its inventor?",
            "answers": ["Fourier Transform"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Argentine footballer is known for his low center of gravity and dribbling skills. He began his professional career with FC Barcelona, where he spent over two decades, setting records for the most goals scored for a single club. Renowned for his precise left foot, he has won numerous Ballon d'Or awards, distinguishing him as one of the best players of his generation. In 2021, he made a high-profile transfer to Paris Saint-Germain. What is the name of this iconic soccer player, often cited as one of the greatest footballers of all time?",
            "answers": ["Lionel Messi"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This iconic ballet, first performed in 1877 at the Bolshoi Theatre in Moscow, was initially met with criticism but has since become one of the most beloved ballets worldwide. Its music was composed by Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky, and the ballet's plot revolves around a princess turned into a swan by an evil sorcerer's curse. Known for its demanding choreography, particularly the role of the dual lead of Odette/Odile, this ballet is a staple in the classical repertoire. What is the name of this ballet which was made into a movie starring Natalie Portman?",
            "answers": ["Swan Lake"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This Canadian actor was born in Beirut, Lebanon, in 1964 and first gained major Hollywood attention for his performance in \"Speed.\" Known for his range, he has appeared in everything from romantic comedies like \"Something's Gotta Give\" to supernatural thrillers like \"Constantine.\" Off-screen, he is lauded for his humility and philanthropic efforts, particularly his contributions to cancer research and children\u2019s hospitals. He is also celebrated for his role as Neo in the \"Matrix\" trilogy and as the titular character in the \"John Wick\" film series. What is the name of this versatile and well-respected actor?",
            "answers": ["Keanu Reeves"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This American politician from Louisiana, a member of the Republican Party, has served in the U.S. House of Representatives since 2017. He represents Louisiana's 4th congressional district, which includes the northwestern part of the state. Known for his strong conservative views, he has been a vocal advocate for constitutional conservatism, emphasizing fiscal responsibility, limited government, and traditional family values. In 2023, he was elected as the Speaker of the House, becoming one of the key figures in the national political landscape. What is the name of this politician who currently holds the position of Speaker of the U.S. House of Representatives?",
            "answers": ["Mike Johnson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Flowing through more countries than any other river in the world, this major European waterway starts in the Black Forest mountains of western Germany and extends through Central and Eastern Europe to the Black Sea. It has been a vital conduit for cultural exchange among the diverse regions along its path, historically serving as a long-standing frontier of the Roman Empire. Today, it plays a crucial role in the regions\u2019 commerce, environmental sustainability, and tourism. What is the name of this second-longest river in Europe, known for connecting ten countries?",
            "answers": ["The Danube"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This iconic national park, located in California's Sierra Nevada mountains, was established in 1890. It was created largely due to the advocacy of naturalist John Muir. It includes one of the tallest waterfalls in North America as well as giant, ancient sequoia trees, and spectacular granite cliffs. What is the name of this national park known for its stunning natural beauty?",
            "answers": ["Yosemite National Park"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Known for his extraordinary height for a sprinter, this Jamaican athlete revolutionized the science of sprinting, focusing heavily on his start technique and stride efficiency. He set the world record for the 100 meters, 200 meters, and 4x100 meters relay, and his iconic celebration pose has become synonymous with his name. Dominating three consecutive Olympic Games, he secured gold medals in all three sprint events at Beijing 2008, London 2012, and Rio 2016. What is the name of this athlete, often referred to as the fastest man alive?",
            "answers": ["Usain Bolt"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Invented by Nikola Tesla in the late 19th century, this electrical resonant transformer circuit is used to produce high-voltage, low-current, high-frequency alternating-current electricity. Notable for creating impressive electrical arcs and being used in entertainment and educational displays, it was originally developed as part of Tesla's experiments with wireless lighting and electrical power distribution. What is the name of this device that exemplifies Tesla\u2019s work in electrical engineering?",
            "answers": ["Tesla Coil", "coil"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This 2010 science fiction film directed by Christopher Nolan features a skilled thief who can enter people's dreams to steal secrets from their subconscious. His greatest challenge involves a complex task where he must implant an idea into a CEO's mind through a layered dream sequence. Known for its elaborate visual effects and a plot that weaves through various levels of consciousness, the film is also famous for its open-ended conclusion, symbolized by a spinning top. What is the name of this critically acclaimed film that explores the concept of dream manipulation?",
            "answers": ["\"Inception\""],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Founded in 1769, this Ivy League institution was originally established to educate Native Americans in Christian theology and the English way of life. This university was the first of an elite group of American universities to bring back a requirement for ACT or SAT scores after the COVID-19 pandemic. Name this Ivy League school located in Hanover, New Hampshire.",
            "answers": ["Dartmouth"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This document, originally issued in 1215, was a result of the political crisis between King John of England and a group of rebel barons within his kingdom. It was first drafted by the Archbishop of Canterbury to make peace between the unpopular King and the rebels. Over time, it has become a symbol of liberty and the rule of law, particularly noted for its role in shaping the legal system of the British constitutional monarchy. What is the name of this historic charter often credited as a foundational document for modern democracy?",
            "answers": ["Magna Carta"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This pivotal event was triggered by legislation passed in 1773 that aimed to rescue the financially struggling British East India Company. It involved a late-night act of rebellion where protestors, some disguised as Mohawk Indians, boarded three ships in a famous harbor. What is this event, famously associated with the phrase \"No taxation without representation\"?",
            "answers": ["The Boston Tea Party"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This figure from Norse mythology is known for his cunning and deceptive nature, often causing as much trouble for the other gods as he resolves. A shape-shifter capable of changing both form and gender, he plays a pivotal role in many myths, including the events leading up to Ragnarok, the end of the world in Norse legend. His complex character has inspired various modern portrayals, including a popular supervillain in the Marvel Cinematic Universe. Known as the Norse god of mischief, what is his name?",
            "answers": ["Loki"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Holding about 90% of the world\u2019s ice and 70% of its fresh water, this continent is crucial for global climate regulation. Governed by an international treaty that designates it as a scientific preserve and prohibits military activity, it has no indigenous human population and supports only temporary research communities. The extreme environment, featuring the coldest temperatures recorded on Earth, facilitates studies ranging from glaciology to climate science. What is the name of this continent, renowned for its expansive ice sheets and unique legal status?",
            "answers": ["Antarctica"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "The first successful use of this invention was achieved in 1903 in Kitty Hawk, North Carolina. The initial use lasted only 12 seconds but covered 120 feet. Today, it is integral to global transportation and commerce. This invention revolutionized travel and military strategy, leading to the first nonstop transatlantic flight in 1919. What is this device which was invented by the Wright Brothers?",
            "answers": ["airplane", "plane"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Developed in the early 21st century, this groundbreaking biotechnological tool allows for precise editing of the DNA in the genomes of living organisms. It utilizes a component of a bacterial immune system, which captures pieces of DNA from viruses, to make precise cuts in specific DNA sequences. This innovation has transformed genetic research, offering potential treatments for a myriad of genetic diseases and advancements in agricultural science. What is the name of this powerful gene-editing technology?",
            "answers": ["CRISPR", "CRISPR-Cas9"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Originating in Asia and spreading via the Silk Road, this pandemic reached Europe in the mid-14th century, causing massive social upheaval and labor shortages due to its high mortality rate. The pathogen was transmitted by fleas carried on black rats aboard trading ships, leading to rapid spread through congested urban areas. Characterized by painful swellings called buboes, this devastating outbreak is known as one of the deadliest pandemics in human history. What is this historical epidemic commonly called?",
            "answers": ["The Black Death", "bubonic plague", "black plague"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "In the arid regions surrounding this hypersaline lake, ancient manuscripts that include some of the earliest known religious texts were discovered, offering significant insights into early religious practices. Located at the lowest land elevation on Earth, this body of water allows swimmers to float effortlessly due to its extremely high salinity, which also supports a thriving health and cosmetics industry based on its mineral-rich mud. Bordered by Jordan to the east and Israel and the West Bank to the west, what is the name of this unique lake renowned for its buoyancy and therapeutic properties?",
            "answers": ["Dead Sea"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This prestigious tennis tournament, known for its unique tradition of consuming strawberries and cream by spectators, maintains a strict no-play policy on the middle Sunday to allow the grass courts to rest. Established in 1877, it is the oldest tennis tournament in the world and is particularly noted for its requirement that players wear all-white attire. Celebrated for being played on outdoor grass courts, this event is one of the four Grand Slam tournaments held annually. What is the name of this tournament, regarded as the most prestigious in the sport of tennis?",
            "answers": ["Wimbledon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Launched in 2016, this Netflix original series combines 1980s nostalgia with supernatural and horror elements. Set in the fictional town of Hawkins, Indiana, the story begins with the mysterious disappearance of a young boy, which leads to revelations about secret government experiments and a girl with psychokinetic abilities. Created by the Duffer Brothers, this series has become a cultural phenomenon. What is the name of this show?",
            "answers": ["\"Stranger Things\""],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This U.S. government agency is responsible for tax collection and tax law enforcement. It administers the Internal Revenue Code enacted by Congress. Established in 1862 during the presidency of Abraham Lincoln, its primary purpose was to fund the Civil War. The agency is also known for its role in the annual observance of April 15th as Tax Day, the deadline for filing individual tax returns. In recent years, it has implemented various modernization efforts to improve taxpayer service and compliance. What is the name of this agency tasked with ensuring the nation's tax laws are followed?",
            "answers": ["Internal Revenue Service", "IRS"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This British author began his career as a political journalist before achieving fame with serialized novels that highlighted the social and economic challenges of Victorian England. Notable for exploring themes like poverty, child labor, and social injustice, his vivid characters and detailed settings have made works such as \"Oliver Twist,\" \"David Copperfield,\" and \"A Christmas Carol\" enduring classics. Name this author whose works have been adapted into numerous plays and films, continuing to influence popular culture.",
            "answers": ["Charles Dickens"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Scheduled to be the third time this city has hosted the Summer Olympics, the 2024 event plans to integrate iconic landmarks as backdrops for competitions. This edition of the Games will also introduce breakdancing as an official Olympic sport. What is the host nation for the olympics which will feature beach volleyball at the foot of the Eiffel Tower and fencing at the Grand Palais?",
            "answers": ["Paris", "Paris, France"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American basketball legend is renowned for his six NBA championships with the Chicago Bulls and two Olympic gold medals. Known for his scoring ability, defensive skills, and clutch performances, he won five MVP awards and is often regarded as the greatest basketball player of all time. What is the name of this iconic athlete, also famous for his global brand and \"Air Jordan\" sneakers?",
            "answers": ["Michael Jordan", "jordan", "air jordan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This public health concept occurs when a sufficient proportion of a population becomes immune to an infectious disease, either through vaccination or previous infections, thus providing indirect protection to those who are not immune. It helps control the spread of contagious diseases and is crucial for protecting vulnerable individuals who cannot be vaccinated. What is the term used to describe this phenomenon, which plays a key role in preventing outbreaks and achieving disease control?",
            "answers": ["Herd Immunity"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Initiated as a military project during the Cold War, this early computer network was developed by the Advanced Research Projects Agency. The first message sent on this network was supposed to be \"LOGIN\" but famously crashed after the first two letters. This network employed packet switching and was a precursor to the modern Internet. What is the name of this groundbreaking project that fundamentally changed the way information is disseminated and communicated globally?",
            "answers": ["ARPANET"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This famous mural painting by an Italian Renaissance artist depicts Jesus Christ's final meal with his apostles before his crucifixion, as described in the Gospel of John. Notable for its detailed representation of the apostles' reactions and the use of perspective, it is located in the Convent of Santa Maria delle Grazie in Milan. What is the name of this masterpiece, created by Leonardo da Vinci?",
            "answers": ["\"The Last Supper\"", "last supper"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This monarch, born in 1819, was known for her strict standards of personal morality and a lengthy reign that saw the expansion of the British Empire. Her era is often associated with the height of the Industrial Revolution. She was the granddaughter of King George III and the mother of nine children. Name this queen, whose name defines an entire age of British history.",
            "answers": ["Queen Victoria"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This 1977 album by a British-American rock band is one of the best-selling albums of all time, noted for its production quality and harmonious sound despite the band members' tumultuous relationships at the time. Hits like \"Go Your Own Way,\" \"Dreams,\" and \"The Chain\" have made it a classic. What is the name of this Fleetwood Mac album, which was largely influenced by personal strife among band members?",
            "answers": ["Rumours", "rumors"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This tropical paradise is made up of 26 atolls in the Indian Ocean, comprising over 1,000 coral islands. Known for its beaches, blue lagoons, and extensive reefs, the country is also the lowest-lying nation in the world, with an average ground level of just 1.5 meters above sea level. It gained independence from British protection in 1965. What is the name of this island nation, renowned for its vibrant marine life and luxury resorts?",
            "answers": ["The Maldives", "maldives"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This European mountain range features the Great St Bernard Pass, a historical route used since Roman times, and is renowned for its extensive ski resorts and hiking trails. Stretching approximately 1,200 kilometers across eight countries including France, Switzerland, Italy, and Austria. The range includes Mont Blanc, the highest peak at 4,809 meters. What is the name of this prominent mountain range known for its scenic beauty and outdoor recreational opportunities?",
            "answers": ["The Alps", "alps"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This poem, first published in 1845, is known for its melodic and dramatic qualities, exploring themes of despair, longing, and the torment of loss. The narrative follows a grieving man who encounters a mysterious raven, whose repeated word \"Nevermore\" enhances the poem's atmosphere of melancholy and doom. Written by an American writer famous for his tales and poems of horror and mystery, what is the name of this poem by Edgar Allan Poe?",
            "answers": ["The Raven"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This device, first successfully demonstrated in 1876, transformed global communication. Its early versions transmitted sound over a single wire, often requiring operators to connect calls. The inventor originally considered it an improvement to the telegraph. What device was famously first used by Alexander Graham Bell to summin his assistant with the words, \"Mr. Watson, come here, I want to see you\"?",
            "answers": ["telephone", "phone"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This type of vaccine uses a synthetic strand of genetic material called messenger RNA to instruct cells in the body to produce a protein similar to one found in a virus. This protein triggers an immune response, preparing the body to fight the actual virus if encountered. First widely used during the COVID-19 pandemic, what is this innovative category of vaccines called?",
            "answers": ["mRNA Vaccines", "mrna"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Founded by a Roman Emperor in 330 AD, this city served as a capital for the Roman, Byzantine, and Ottoman empires. Renowned for its strategic position between Europe and Asia, it was pivotal in controlling the passage between the Black Sea and the Mediterranean. The city fell to the Ottoman Empire in 1453, an event that marked the end of the Byzantine Empire. It was later renamed Istanbul. Name this historically significant city that was once known as the \"Queen of Cities.\"",
            "answers": [
                "Constantinople",
                "The Fall of Constantinople",
                "siege of constantionple",
                "constantinople"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This German Formula One driver is renowned for his seven World Championships, tying him with Lewis Hamilton for the most titles in the history of the sport. Known for his precision driving and competitiveness, he drove for teams like Benetton and Ferrari, where he helped build the latter into one of the most successful teams in F1 history. What is the name of this legendary driver, often celebrated as one of the greatest Formula One racers ever?",
            "answers": ["Michael Schumacher", "Mick Schumacher"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This iconic American television series, created by Rod Serling, premiered in 1959 and is renowned for its twist endings and moral lessons. The show blended elements of science fiction, horror, and fantasy to explore complex social and existential themes through standalone, often surreal narratives. What is the name of this groundbreaking anthology series?",
            "answers": ["The Twilight Zone", "twilight zone"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This popular online puzzle game, created by software engineer Josh Wardle, quickly gained a massive following after its release in 2021. The game challenges players to guess a five-letter word within six attempts, using color-coded feedback to show correct letters and placements. Its simple yet engaging format led to its acquisition by The New York Times. What is the name of this daily word game that has become a global phenomenon?",
            "answers": ["Wordle"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This German composer and pianist was a crucial figure in the transition between the Classical and Romantic eras in Western music. His compositions include 9 symphonies, 5 piano concertos, and a significant number of sonatas, among them the famously emotive \u201cMoonlight Sonata.\u201d Despite his progressive hearing loss, he continued to compose some of his greatest works, which remain central to the music repertoire today. What is the name of this influential composer, known for his symphony \u201cOde to Joy\u201d?",
            "answers": ["Ludwig van Beethoven", "beethoven"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Established after World War I as part of the Treaty of Versailles in 1920, this international organization was intended to maintain world peace and prevent future conflicts. Despite its efforts, it struggled with membership and enforcement power, failing to stop aggression from Axis powers in the 1930s. It was eventually replaced by the United Nations after World War II. Name this precursor to the United Nations, which aimed to promote diplomatic dialogue and collective security.",
            "answers": ["The League of Nations"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Swiss tennis player, renowned for his graceful play and sportsmanship, has won 20 Grand Slam singles titles, a record he held until surpassed by his rivals. Known for his prowess on grass courts, especially at Wimbledon where he has won a record eight times, he is celebrated as one of the greatest tennis players of all time. What is the name of this legendary tennis icon?",
            "answers": ["Roger Federer"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This computer launched in 1977 as one of the first to come with a color display and was sold as a fully assembled circuit board. It included a keyboard and was notably user-friendly, which helped it stand out in a market dominated by technical kits for hobbyists. Name this early PC that helped launch the personal computer revolution and solidified its company, founded by two Steves, as a key player in the technology sector.",
            "answers": ["Apple II", "Apple 2"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "These computational systems are inspired by the biological neural networks that constitute animal brains. Utilized in machine learning, they are composed of layers of interconnected nodes or \"neurons\" that can learn to recognize patterns and make decisions by adjusting the strength of the connections based on the data they process. What is the term for these powerful tools in artificial intelligence that mimic the structure and function of the human brain?",
            "answers": ["Neural Networks"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This American businessman and television personality turned politician was known for his real estate ventures and the reality TV show \"The Apprentice\" before entering the political arena. In 2016, he won the U.S. presidential election as the Republican candidate, becoming the 45th President of the United States. Noted for his unconventional approach to politics and governance, he is also the first president without prior military or government service. What is the name of this figure, who was impeached twice during his term?",
            "answers": ["Donald Trump"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This 1993 film, directed by Steven Spielberg, is noted for its poignant use of black and white cinematography, and it won seven Academy Awards, including Best Picture. It tells the story of a German businessman who saved over a thousand Polish-Jewish refugees during the Holocaust by employing them in his factories. What is the name of this powerful historical drama?",
            "answers": ["Schindler's List"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This mountain range extends over 7,000 kilometers and is known for its varied climates, from arid to one of the wettest places on Earth. It is home to many unique species and reaches its highest point at Mount Aconcagua, which is the highest peak outside Asia. Passing through seven countries, it is the longest continental mountain range located along the western coast of South America. What is the name of this significant mountain range?",
            "answers": ["The Andes", "Andes"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This iconic statue representing a Roman goddess was designed by Fr\u00e9d\u00e9ric Auguste Bartholdi and dedicated on October 28, 1886. It features a broken chain at its feet, symbolizing freedom and the abolition of slavery. The statue's exterior is made of copper sheets, which have oxidized to form its green patina. Initially, it served as a lighthouse, guiding ships into New York Harbor. What is this American landmark commonly known as?",
            "answers": ["Statue of Liberty"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This ancient civilization, known for its road systems, architectural achievements like the Colosseum, and influential legal structures, became one of the largest empires in history. It reached its peak under Emperor Trajan and eventually split into Western and Eastern segments. The empire began expanding from a city on the Italian Peninsula in the 8th century BC. Name this empire, famous for its vast influence across Europe.",
            "answers": ["The Roman Empire", "roman"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This term describes the boundary around a black hole beyond which no radiation can escape. It shares its name with a 1997 sci-fi horror film that explores a spaceship encountering a similar boundary in space. The concept was first detailed by the German astronomer Karl Schwarzschild. What is this term, which marks the limits of a black hole's gravitational influence?",
            "answers": ["Event Horizon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This American filmmaker directed iconic films across genres, including \"2001: A Space Odyssey\" and \"The Shining.\" Known for his meticulous craftsmanship and thematic complexity, his works are celebrated for innovative cinematography and deep philosophical underpinnings. What is the name of this influential director whose style has left a lasting impact on the film industry?",
            "answers": ["Stanley Kubrick"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American golfer has won 15 major championships, including five Masters Tournaments. Famous for his red shirt on final-round Sundays and his influence in making golf a global sport, he is one of the most recognized and highest-earning athletes in the world. What is the name of this iconic golfer, often referred to simply by his first name?",
            "answers": ["Tiger Woods", "tiger"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known for its two major tributaries with the names, Blue and White, this river traverses eleven countries, including Uganda, Sudan, and Egypt. It plays a vital role in agriculture, particularly for Egyptian civilizations since ancient times. Flowing northward through northeastern Africa and draining into the Mediterranean Sea, this is recognized as the longest river in the world. What is the name of this significant African river?",
            "answers": ["The Nile River", "nile"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This novel, published in 1922 by an Irish author, is known for its stream of consciousness technique and deep exploration of the mundane activities of its characters during a single day in Dublin. The narrative parallels the structure of Homer\u2019s epic, \"The Odyssey,\" with its characters reflecting modern versions of those from the ancient text. What is the name of this complex and highly influential modernist work by James Joyce?",
            "answers": ["\"Ulysses\"", "ulysses"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This region, located on the eastern coast of the Mediterranean Sea, has been a focal point of conflict between Israel and Hamas. The conflict in this region grew into a full war after terrorist attacks by Hamas in Israel on October 7, 2023. What is the name of this territory that has been at the center of protracted and intense geopolitical strife?",
            "answers": ["Gaza Strip", "Gaza"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This series of approximately 250 oil paintings by a French Impressionist captures the artist's flower garden at his home in Giverny, with the main focus on a pond. Created during the last 30 years of his life, these paintings show the artist's shifting focus from representing the garden's landscape to the play of light and shadow across the pond's surface. What is the name of this series by Claude Monet, celebrated for its exploration of perception and natural beauty?",
            "answers": ["Water Lilies"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This pivotal event of World War II occurred on June 6, 1944. The planning of this operation was shrouded in secrecy, utilizing deception techniques such as fake equipment and phantom armies. It involved the largest amphibious invasion in history with the use of over 5,000 vessels and 13,000 aircraft and marked a turning point in the war against Nazi Germany. Originally codenamed Operation Overlord, what is this historic day commonly known as?",
            "answers": ["D-Day", "D Day", "Battle of Normandy"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1995, this groundbreaking film was the first feature-length movie created entirely using computer-generated imagery (CGI). It tells the story of a group of toys that come to life when humans aren't looking, led by Woody the cowboy and Buzz Lightyear, a space ranger. This film set new standards in animation and launched a successful franchise. What is the name of this pioneering animated film produced by Pixar?",
            "answers": ["Toy Story"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NBA team has a storied history with 17 championships, tying them for the most in league history. Known for their purple and gold colors, they have been home to basketball legends such as Magic Johnson, Kobe Bryant, and LeBron James. What is the name of this iconic basketball franchise based in Los Angeles?",
            "answers": ["Los Angeles Lakers", "Lakers"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This Asian mountain range is known for containing many of the world's highest peaks, including over 100 that exceed 7,200 meters. It is home to the famous K2 and the highest point on Earth, Mount Everest. The range also forms a natural barrier between the Indian subcontinent and the Tibetan Plateau. What is the name of this extensive mountain range, crucial for its climatic impact and cultural significance in the regions it spans?",
            "answers": ["The Himalayas", "himalayan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This port city in southeastern Ukraine became a focal point during the Russo-Ukrainian War. Heavily industrialized, it is strategically located on the coast of the Sea of Azov, linking it directly to the Black Sea. In 2022, the city endured a significant siege that resulted in widespread destruction and a humanitarian crisis, highlighting the severe impacts of the conflict. What is the name of this city which was subject of an Oscar-winning documentary in 2023?",
            "answers": ["Mariupol"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "First predicted by Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity in 1916, these ripples in spacetime are generated by some of the most violent and energetic processes in the Universe, such as colliding black holes or exploding stars. They were directly detected for the first time in 2015 by the LIGO observatory, confirming a major prediction of Einstein's theory. What are these disturbances in spacetime that share a name with an essential physical force called?",
            "answers": ["Gravitational Waves"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This decisive battle took place on June 18, 1815, near Brussels. It featured a coalition of armies led by the Duke of Wellington and a Prussian army under General Bl\u00fccher, who faced Napoleon Bonaparte\u2019s French troops, and marked the end of the Napoleonic Wars. The defeat led to Napoleon's abdication and exile to Saint Helena. Name this battle, often cited as one of the major turning points in European history.",
            "answers": ["The Battle of Waterloo", "waterloo"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Formed by volcanic activity, this archipelago consists of hundreds of islands spread over 1,500 miles in the central Pacific Ocean. It became the 50th U.S. state in 1959 and is known for its rich cultural heritage. The state's major islands include Oahu, Maui, Kauai, and the Big Island. What is the name of this U.S. state, celebrated for its natural beauty?",
            "answers": ["Hawaii", "The Hawaiian Islands", "hawaii"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Founded by Osman I in the late 13th century, this empire expanded across three continents at its peak under Suleiman the Magnificent. Known for its military prowess and cultural synthesis, it significantly influenced Southeastern Europe, Western Asia, and Northern Africa. Name this empire, which had a capital of Constantinople and dissolved after World War I.",
            "answers": [
                "The Ottoman Empire",
                "Ottoman Empire",
                "Turkish Empire"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This British Formula One driver has matched the record for the most World Championships in the sport, with seven titles, sharing this achievement with Michael Schumacher. Known for his skillful driving and advocacy for social issues, he has raced predominantly for Mercedes-Benz and has set numerous records, including the most career wins. What is the name of this influential and successful Formula One racer?",
            "answers": ["Lewis Hamilton"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This American politician served as a U.S. Senator from Delaware for 36 years before becoming Vice President under Barack Obama from 2009 to 2017. Known for his work on foreign relations, criminal justice, and domestic policy issues, he won the presidential election in 2020 to become the 46th President of the United States. What is the name of this President, notable for being the oldest person inaugurated to this office?",
            "answers": ["Joe Biden"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This American musical blends hip-hop, jazz, R&B, and Broadway styles to tell the story of a forgotten Founding Father. It was inspired by a 2004 biography and features a racially diverse cast to reflect America's contemporary composition rather than its historical one. The show's creator, who also originated the title role, earned widespread acclaim for his innovative approach to storytelling. What is the name of this groundbreaking musical that reimagines the life of Alexander Hamilton?",
            "answers": ["Hamilton"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This day in U.S. history witnessed a brave act of passenger resistance aboard United Flight 93, which resulted in the plane crashing into a field in Pennsylvania, thwarting the hijackers' intended attack on the nation's capital. The aftermath of the attacks on this day saw significant changes in U.S. policy, including the establishment of the Department of Homeland Security and stricter aviation security measures. The same day, other hijacked planes struck the World Trade Center and the Pentagon. What is the date of these pivotal events known as in American history?",
            "answers": [
                "9/11",
                "9/11/2001",
                "9/11/01",
                "September 11",
                "September 11 2001"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This popular American sitcom, which debuted in 1994, follows the lives of six friends living in New York City as they navigate the ups and downs of adulthood. Known for its witty dialogue, memorable one-liners, and iconic coffee shop setting, the show remained a top-rated TV show throughout its ten-season run. It has left a lasting impact on television comedy. What is the name of this beloved sitcom?",
            "answers": ["Friends"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This graph, first plotted by scientist Charles David Keeling in 1958, shows the concentration of atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) based on continuous measurements taken at the Mauna Loa Observatory in Hawaii. It is considered one of the most important scientific contributions to the understanding of global climate change because it provides clear evidence of rising CO2 levels over decades. What is this iconic graph that tracks the increasing presence of a key greenhouse gas in Earth's atmosphere called?",
            "answers": ["Keeling Curve"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Revered as sacred by millions, particularly in Hinduism, this river supports one of the world\u2019s highest population densities and is central to agriculture in both India and Bangladesh. Historically significant for centuries, it originates in the Indian Himalayas and flows over 2,525 kilometers into the Bay of Bengal. What is the name of this vital South Asian river?",
            "answers": ["The Ganges River", "Ganges"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Proposed by a British theoretical physicist in 1974, this theoretical prediction suggests that black holes are not entirely black but emit radiation due to quantum effects near the event horizon. This radiation implies that black holes can slowly lose mass and eventually evaporate over astronomical timescales. What is the name of this radiation, named after the scientist who first theorized its existence?",
            "answers": ["Hawking Radiation", "Hawking", "Stephen Hawking"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Italian explorer, sailing under the Spanish flag, set out on his first voyage in 1492 with three ships: the Ni\u00f1a, the Pinta, and the Santa Mar\u00eda. He is often mistakenly credited with being the first European to reach the Americas. His expeditions marked the beginning of European exploration and colonization of the American continents. Name this historical figure whose voyages had a profound impact on the global interactions of the Renaissance era.",
            "answers": ["Christopher Columbus", "columbus"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This Japanese animated film, released in 2001, became critically acclaimed for its rich storytelling and animation. Directed by Hayao Miyazaki and produced by Studio Ghibli, it tells the story of a young girl navigating a world of spirits and gods after her parents are transformed into pigs. Name this film that won the Academy Award for Best Animated Feature, making it the first and only hand-drawn and non-English-language animated film to win the award.",
            "answers": ["Spirited Away"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This politician is the longest serving Senator from New York. Before he was elected to the senate he served nine terms in the House of Represenatives. He was the first Jewish Senate Majority Leader. Name this current Senate Majority Leader who has led the Democrats in the Senate since 2017.",
            "answers": ["Chuck Schumer", "Charles Schumer", "Shumer"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American golfer, known as \"The Golden Bear,\" has won a record 18 major championships, a mark that stands as the benchmark for success in professional golf. Renowned for his powerful play and strategic approach, he won six Masters Tournaments and four U.S. Open titles among his impressive tally. What is the name of this legendary golfer, celebrated for his dominance in the sport's biggest tournaments?",
            "answers": ["Jack Nicklaus"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Initially patented by Joseph Swan, this invention saw significant improvement when a more durable filament material was used by another inventor. It's often associated with a famous American inventor's first major public system of electric illumination. This innovation has evolved into various forms including LED and CFL. What is this invention which is often credited to Thomas Edison and commonly used to illuminate homes and streets?",
            "answers": ["light bulb"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This German composer of the Baroque period is renowned for his intricate compositions and profound influence on the structure of classical music. His works, characterized by their intellectual depth, technical command, and artistic beauty, include the \"Brandenburg Concertos,\" \"The Well-Tempered Clavier,\" and numerous cantatas and fugues. He spent much of his career as a church musician and a Kapellmeister in Leipzig. What is the name of this composer, celebrated for his masterful use of counterpoint and harmony?",
            "answers": ["Johann Sebastian Bach", "bach"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This American singer was involved in a highly publicized incident during the Super Bowl XXXVIII halftime show in 2004, which resulted in a nationwide controversy. The performance concluded with a surprise \"wardrobe malfunction\" during a duet with Justin Timberlake, leading to immediate media backlash and changes in broadcast regulations. What is the name of this artist, whose performance led to the coining of the term \"wardrobe malfunction\"?",
            "answers": ["Janet Jackson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This fundamental concept in quantum mechanics, introduced by a German physicist in 1927, states that it is impossible to simultaneously know both the exact position and exact momentum of a particle. The more precisely one property is measured, the less precisely the other can be controlled or known. This principle challenged classical ideas of exactitude in science. Name the physicist who formulated this principle, which has profound implications for the behavior of subatomic particles.",
            "answers": ["Heisenberg's Uncertainty Principle", "Heisenberg"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This novel, published in 1925 by a prominent English writer, is set in post-World War I London and spans a single day in the life of its protagonist, who prepares for a party she will host that evening. The narrative delves into the complexities of its characters' thoughts and memories, utilizing the stream of consciousness technique to reveal their inner lives. What is the name of this seminal modernist work which follows Clarissa Dalloway by Virginia Woolf?",
            "answers": ["\"Mrs Dalloway\"", "Mrs. Dalloway"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This national soccer team holds the record for the most FIFA World Cup victories, having won the prestigious tournament five times. Known for their skillful play and prominent players like Pel\u00e9 and Ronaldo, they first won in 1958 and secured their latest title in 2002. What is the name of this country's team, celebrated for its rich football heritage and success on the global stage?",
            "answers": ["Brazil"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This city had over 10 inches of rain fall in a 24 hour period in April 2024. This set a record for the last 75 years in this city which lies in a desert nation known for its oil reserves. This city is also home to the world's tallest building, the Burj Khalifa. Name this city which was recently overwhelmed by flooding in the United Arab Emirates.",
            "answers": ["Dubai"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This geological marvel was first seen by European eyes in 1540, part of an expedition led by Spanish explorers. Despite its remote location, it became more accessible after the construction of a railway bearing its name 1901. This natural wonder was designated as a national park in 1919 by President Woodrow Wilson. What is the name of this famous canyon that was carved over millions of years by the Colorado River?",
            "answers": ["Grand Canyon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This mountain range stretches over 3,000 miles from British Columbia to New Mexico and includes Mount Elbert, its highest peak. Known for the Continental Divide, it forms the eastern portion of the North American Cordillera. This range shares a name with a baseball team based in Denver and has been invoked in beer commercials. What is the name of this iconic North American mountain range?",
            "answers": ["The Rockies", "Rocky Mountains", "rockies"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This transformative period began in Britain in the late 18th century and spread to other parts of the world. It was marked by the transition from hand production methods to machines, new chemical manufacturing and iron production processes, and the rise of the factory system. Notable innovations include the steam engine and spinning jenny. Name this era that dramatically changed economies, societies, and environments across the globe.",
            "answers": ["The Industrial Revolution", "industrial age"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This groundbreaking music video, released in 1983 by an American pop star, revolutionized the music industry with its elaborate narrative and dance sequences. Directed by John Landis and featuring iconic zombie dance moves, the video extended over 13 minutes, blending music with cinematic storytelling. It became a global phenomenon and significantly boosted sales of the album of the same name. What is the name of this influential music video by Michael Jackson?",
            "answers": ["Thriller"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This thought experiment in quantum mechanics involves a hypothetical cat that may be simultaneously both alive and dead, depending on an earlier random event. Devised by an Austrian physicist in 1935, it illustrates the concept of superposition\u2014the ability of a quantum system to be in multiple states at once until it is measured. Name the physicist who created this paradoxical experiment to challenge the Copenhagen interpretation of quantum mechanics.",
            "answers": ["Schr\u00f6dinger's Cat", "Schrodinger"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This period of geopolitical tension between the Soviet Union and the United States spanned from 1947 to 1991. Characterized by the arms race, space competition, and various proxy wars, it never escalated into direct military conflict between the two superpowers. Notable events include the Cuban Missile Crisis and the fall of the Berlin Wall. Name this era marked by the struggle for global supremacy without open warfare.",
            "answers": ["The Cold War"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This major North American river is known for its historical importance as a trade route during the era of steamboats. It flows over 2,300 miles from northern Minnesota to the Gulf of Mexico, making it the second-longest river in the United States. The river also passes through or borders ten states, including Illinois, Iowa, and Louisiana. What is the name of this river, vital for its ecological diversity and economic significance in U.S. history?",
            "answers": ["The Mississippi River", "mississippi"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This iconic statue was sculpted by an Italian Renaissance artist between 1501 and 1504 and stands at over 14 feet tall. Originally commissioned as one of a series of statues for Florence Cathedral, it now resides in the Galleria dell'Accademia in Florence. Representing the Biblical hero who defeated Goliath, it is renowned for its detailed anatomy and expression of calm readiness. What is the name of this famous marble sculpture created by Michelangelo?",
            "answers": ["\"David\"", "david"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Known for his charismatic presence and phrases like \"float like a butterfly, sting like a bee,\" this American boxer became a cultural icon beyond the world of sports. He won the world heavyweight championship three times and participated in several historic boxing matches, including the \"Rumble in the Jungle.\" His refusal to serve in the Vietnam War due to his religious beliefs and stance on civil rights brought him significant attention and controversy. What is the name of this legendary boxer, often referred to as \"The Greatest\"?",
            "answers": ["Muhammad Ali"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This U.S. state, known for its desert climate and picturesque landscapes was admitted to the union in 1912 as the 48th state. This state's Supreme Court recently paved the wave for enforcement of a strict abortion restriction which was passed into law during the U.S. Civil War. What is the name of this southwestern state, recognized for its unique cacti and significant Native American history?",
            "answers": ["Arizona"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This individual won a Grammy Award for his audiobook \"Dreams from My Father\" and taught constitutional law at the University of Chicago Law School. He was the first African American president of the Harvard Law Review in 1990. He was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2009. What is the name of this prominent political figure?",
            "answers": ["Barack Obama"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This women's rights advocate and social reformer was arrested and fined for illegally attempting to vote in the 1872 presidential election.  She was once depicted on a dollar coin issued by the U.S. Treasury, though it failed to gain widespread circulation. She co-founded the National Woman Suffrage Association with Elizabeth Cady Stanton. Name this tireless champion of women's rights",
            "answers": ["Susan B. Anthony"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This dormant volcano in Tanzania is known for its three volcanic cones: Kibo, Mawenzi, and Shira. Popular among climbers and trekkers worldwide, it features a snow-capped summit near the equator, despite being located just 205 miles from the equator. Rising about 5,895 meters (19,341 feet) above sea level, it holds the title of the highest mountain in Africa. What is the name of this mountain, a symbol of towering natural beauty and challenge?",
            "answers": ["Mount Kilimanjaro", "Kilimanjaro"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This American director, known for his dynamic storytelling and strong character development, has a long-standing collaboration with actor Robert De Niro, with whom he created classics like \"Taxi Driver\" and \"Raging Bull.\" His films often explore complex themes such as crime, guilt, and redemption. Among his celebrated works is \"Goodfellas,\" a critical and commercial success that redefined the gangster genre. What is the name of this influential filmmaker?",
            "answers": ["Martin Scorsese", "Scorsese", "Marty Scorsese"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American swimmer set the record for the most Olympic medals won by any athlete, totaling 28 medals, including 23 golds. His performances at the 2008 Beijing Olympics, where he won eight gold medals, are particularly celebrated. Who is this legendary swimmer who featured in a series of Subway ads?",
            "answers": ["Michael Phelps"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This musical, based on a French novel of the same name by Gaston Leroux, is renowned for its captivating romance and haunting narrative. It tells the story of a disfigured musical genius, who haunts the Parisian entertainment venue and becomes obsessed with a young soprano, Christine. Composed by Andrew Lloyd Webber, it is one of the longest-running shows on Broadway. What is the name of this iconic musical?",
            "answers": ["The Phantom of the Opera"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This leader implemented the Yassa code to promote trade and communication within his empire, which stretched from Eastern Europe across Asia to the Sea of Japan. He united the nomadic tribes of Northeast Asia, founding the largest contiguous empire in history. His conquests encompassed large parts of Central Asia and China, with his descendants continuing to expand the empire after his death. Name this Mongolian ruler, born in the late 12th century.",
            "answers": ["Genghis Khan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This American politician served as the Attorney General of California and then as a United States Senator before making history in her current role. She became the first female Vice President of the United States in January 2021, also making her the highest-ranking female official in U.S. history, and the first African American and South Asian American to hold this office. What is the name of this groundbreaking political figure?",
            "answers": ["Kamala Harris"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Developed to combat vitamin A deficiency, this genetically modified crop produces beta-carotene in its grain, which the human body can convert into vitamin A. This innovation is especially aimed at improving the health outcomes in developing countries where rice is a staple food but malnutrition is prevalent. What is the colorful name of this biofortified rice that has been altered to address a specific nutritional deficiency?",
            "answers": ["Golden Rice"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known locally as 'Mosi-oa-Tunya,' which translates to 'The Smoke That Thunders,' this natural wonder creates a thunderous roar and a mist that can be seen from miles away. It forms one of the largest curtains of falling water in the world, drawing visitors from all over the globe to its breathtaking views. Designated as a UNESCO World Heritage site, it straddles the border between Zambia and Zimbabwe along the Zambezi River. What is the name of this magnificent waterfall, celebrated as one of the Seven Natural Wonders of the World?",
            "answers": ["Victoria Falls"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Launched in 1588 by King Philip II of Spain, this fleet was one of the largest maritime fleets in European history, consisting of 130 ships manned by 8,000 sailors and over 18,000 soldiers. Its mission was to overthrow Queen Elizabeth I of England and halt the influence of Protestantism in Europe. Despite its formidable size, the fleet suffered a disastrous defeat due to a combination of strategic miscalculations, stormy weather, and effective tactics by the English navy. What is this famous naval campaign commonly known as, which marked a pivotal moment in Anglo-Spanish relations?",
            "answers": ["The Spanish Armada"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This novel intricately portrays the clash of cultures between feudal Japan and the Western world during the early 17th century. It is based on the historical adventures of an English navigator who becomes a samurai and political player within the Japanese feudal system. Published in 1975, it became a bestseller and was later adapted into a successful television miniseries in 1980 and again in 2024. What is the name of this historical novel by James Clavell that explores the rise of a foreigner in the Japanese samurai-led society?",
            "answers": ["Shogun"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This scientist was born in 1822 in a region now part of the Czech Republic and initially entered a monastery where he could receive an education. He conducted hybridization experiments in the monastery's garden, using pea plants to study inheritance patterns. His work laid the foundation for the modern understanding of genetics, though it was largely ignored during his lifetime. What is the name of this pioneer of genetic research, known for his laws of inheritance?",
            "answers": ["Gregor Mendel"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Before becoming president, this man owned a whiskey distillery, one of the largest in the nation. From 1749 to 1750, he served in his first public office as surveyor of Culpeper County in the Colony of Virginia. This Founding Father led the Continental Army in battle against the British during the Revolutionary War. Name this general and first president of the United States.",
            "answers": ["George Washington"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Published in 1925, this iconic American novel captures the spirit of the Roaring Twenties with its themes of decadence, idealism, and the pursuit of the American Dream. Narrated by Nick Carraway, the story delves into the lives of the wealthy occupants of Long Island's North Shore, focusing on his mysterious and affluent neighbor's quest to reunite with a former lover. Celebrated for its sharp critique of social stratification and the elusive nature of happiness, this novel remains a staple of American literature. What is the title of this F. Scott Fitzgerald work, emblematic of the Jazz Age?",
            "answers": ["\"The Great Gatsby\"", "great gatsby"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This British singer-songwriter rose to fame with her debut album \"19,\" and further captivated audiences worldwide with her soulful voice in the follow-up album \"21,\" which included hits like \"Rolling in the Deep\" and \"Someone Like You.\" Known for her deep, expressive vocals and poignant lyrics, her music often explores themes of love, heartbreak, and self-reflection. Winning multiple Grammy Awards, she has become one of the best-selling music artists of the 21st century. What is the name of this influential artist whose third album, \"25,\" continued her streak of chart-topping success?",
            "answers": ["Adele"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This annual event, established in 1897, is the world's oldest annual marathon and ranks as one of the world's most prestigious road racing events. It is held on Patriots' Day, the third Monday of April. The race starts in rural Hopkinton. Notably, it was the scene of a tragic event in 2013 when bombings near the finish line resulted in widespread injuries and loss of life. What is the name of this historic marathon known for its challenging course and storied history?",
            "answers": ["The Boston Marathon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1990, this hit song by an iconic pop artist became a global sensation, topping the charts in over 30 countries and becoming one of the best-selling singles of all time. The track is known for its influence on dance and fashion, highlighted in its stylish black-and-white music video, which drew inspiration from 1920s and 1930s Hollywood cinema. What is the name of this influential song by Madonna that brought a specific underground dance style into mainstream pop culture?",
            "answers": ["Vogue"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This former NFL running back is celebrated for his storied career with the Dallas Cowboys, where he became the league's all-time leading rusher. Over his 15 seasons, primarily with the Cowboys and later with the Arizona Cardinals, he amassed 18,355 rushing yards, setting a record that still stands. Known for his durability and powerful running style, he played a key role in helping his team secure three Super Bowl victories in the 1990s. Inducted into the Pro Football Hall of Fame in 2010, his legacy as one of the greatest running backs in history is well secured. What is the name of this legendary NFL player?",
            "answers": ["Emmitt Smith"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This tribunal was notorious for its use of torture and public executions, it primarily targeted converted Jews and Muslims suspected of secretly practicing their old religions. It was established in 1478 by Ferdinand II of Aragon and Isabella I of Castile, and it aimed to enforce Catholic orthodoxy in Spain. What is the name of this period of intense religious scrutiny and persecution?",
            "answers": [
                "Spanish Inquisition",
                "Inquisition",
                "Tribunal of the Holy Office of the Inquisition"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This 1803 event dramatically altered the size and shape of the United States, adding approximately 828,000 square miles of territory. It involved a deal with Napoleon Bonaparte of France, who needed funds for his military campaigns. The acquisition doubled the size of the young nation and included land that would become fifteen different states. At less than three cents an acre, it remains one of the largest land deals in history. What is the name of this significant expansion of U.S. territory?",
            "answers": ["Louisiana Purchase"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This American author, known for his legal thrillers, published his first novel, \"A Time to Kill,\" in 1989, drawing upon his experiences as a lawyer and legislator in Mississippi. He gained widespread fame with his second book, \"The Firm,\" which became a bestseller and was adapted into a successful film starring Tom Cruise. Many of his subsequent novels, including \"The Pelican Brief\" and \"The Client,\" have also been turned into popular movies. What is the name of this prolific writer whose works frequently explore legal and moral issues?",
            "answers": ["John Grisham"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known for its iconic Joshua trees and stark beauty, this desert features unique ecosystems and landmarks such as Death Valley, the hottest place on earth. It is the driest desert in North America and plays a significant role in renewable energy development, particularly solar power. Spanning across southeastern California, Nevada, and small parts of Utah and Arizona, what is the name of this arid region in the United States?",
            "answers": ["The Mojave Desert", "Mojave"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "First proposed by a German mathematician in 1859, this conjecture deals with the zeros of the Riemann zeta function, asserting that all non-trivial zeros have real parts of one-half. It has significant implications for the distribution of prime numbers and remains one of the most important unsolved problems in mathematics. This hypothesis is also one of the seven Millennium Prize Problems, offering a million-dollar reward for a proof. What is the name of this renowned mathematical hypothesis?",
            "answers": ["Riemann Hypothesis"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This entrepreneur, originally from China, has made significant strides in the cryptocurrency industry as the founder and CEO of one of the world's largest cryptocurrency exchanges by trading volume. Established in 2017, his company, Binance, quickly rose to prominence in the crypto community. What is the name of this influential figure in the cryptocurrency world who was sentenced to four months in prison for money laundering charges in April 2024?",
            "answers": ["Changpeng Zhao", "CZ"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This major WWII battle, fought during the winter of 1944-1945, was the largest and bloodiest battle involving American forces. It occurred when German troops launched a massive counteroffensive in the Ardennes region, aiming to split Allied lines. Despite initial success, the Allies ultimately contained the German advance, marking the last major Nazi offensive on the Western Front. What is the name of this pivotal battle?",
            "answers": ["Battle of the Bulge", "Ardennes Offensive"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This desert, often used by scientists as a Mars-like environment for testing space-bound equipment, features vast salt flats, sand, and lava flows. It is known for spectacular flower blooms that occasionally appear following rare rainfalls. Stretching across northern Chile and into parts of Peru, Bolivia, and Argentina, this region is renowned as one of the driest places on Earth. What is the name of this extremely arid region?",
            "answers": ["The Atacama Desert", "Atacama"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This professional ice hockey team, based in Ontario, Canada, is one of the \"Original Six\" members of the National Hockey League. Founded in 1917, they have a storied history and a passionate fan base, known for their long-standing rivalries with teams like the Montreal Canadiens and the Detroit Red Wings. Despite their success in the early years, they hold one of the longest Stanley Cup droughts, having not won since 1967. They play their home games at Scotiabank Arena. What is the name of this NHL team, famous for its blue and white uniforms?",
            "answers": ["Toronto Maple Leafs", "Maple Leafs"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered independently by Carl Wilhelm Scheele and Joseph Priestley in the 1770s, this element is essential for cellular respiration in most aerobic organisms and is the most abundant element by mass in the Earth's crust. Comprising approximately 21% of the Earth's atmosphere, it is vital for combustion processes and is commonly used in medical treatments for respiratory illnesses. What is the name of this colorless, odorless, tasteless gas that is critical for life on Earth?",
            "answers": ["Oxygen", "O2"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Originating in 12th-century France and lasting into the 16th century, this style of architecture is renowned for its verticality and light-filled interiors. Characterized by features such as pointed arches, ribbed vaults, and flying buttresses, it supported taller structures and larger windows than were previously possible. Notable examples include the Notre-Dame Cathedral in Paris and the Cologne Cathedral in Germany. This style also marked a significant shift from the solid, heavy forms of Romanesque architecture to a more ornate aesthetic. What is the name of this architectural style that flourished during the high and late medieval period?",
            "answers": ["Gothic"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This year featured a series of pivotal moments in American history, including the iconic Woodstock music festival, which symbolized the peak of the counterculture movement. It also witnessed the monumental first manned moon landing by Apollo 11, where Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin famously walked on the lunar surface. Additionally, Richard Nixon was inaugurated as the 37th president of the United States during this significant year. In which year did all these historic events occur?",
            "answers": ["1969"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "First celebrated in 1970, this annual event marks the anniversary of the birth of the modern environmental movement. It was founded by U.S. Senator Gaylord Nelson as a way to promote ecology and raise awareness of the growing problems of air, water, and soil pollution. This day encourages environmental action by individuals, communities, and governments around the world to combat issues like climate change and habitat destruction. Activities include planting trees, cleaning up trash, and campaigns for recycling and conservation. What is the name of this global observance dedicated to protecting the planet?",
            "answers": ["Earth Day"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 2008, this film features a memorable performance by Heath Ledger in a role that won him a posthumous Oscar for Best Supporting Actor. It is the second installment in Christopher Nolan's Batman trilogy and is celebrated for its complex characters and dark psychological depth. It f The movie's critical and commercial success helped redefine superhero films as a genre capable of serious storytelling. Set in the fictional Gotham City, it explores themes of chaos, morality, and heroism. What is the title of this influential superhero film?",
            "answers": ["The Dark Knight"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This Spanish archipelago is renowned for its vibrant nightlife and beautiful beaches. It includes the Serra de Tramuntana mountain range in Mallorca, a UNESCO World Heritage site, and features historical megalithic stone monuments on Menorca. The group consists of four major islands: Mallorca, Menorca, Ibiza, and Formentera, located in the Mediterranean Sea. What is the collective name of these islands?",
            "answers": ["The Balearic Islands", "Balearic Islands"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This novel, first published in 1851, is a complex tale of a monomaniacal quest for revenge set against the backdrop of the 19th-century whaling industry. The narrative is driven by the obsessive Captain Ahab, commander of the whaling ship Pequod, who seeks vengeance on a giant white whale that once maimed him. The book explores themes of fate, nature, and the struggles between man and the sea. Written by Herman Melville, what is the title of this classic American novel that begins with the famous line, \"Call me Ishmael\"?",
            "answers": ["Moby Dick"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Known as \"El Libertador,\" this influential figure was instrumental in the early 19th-century movements that led to the independence of several South American countries from Spanish rule. His military and political leadership contributed to the liberation of present-day Venezuela, Bolivia, Colombia, Ecuador, Peru, and Panama. Born in Caracas, he is revered as a national hero in many Latin American countries, and his vision of a united South America remains influential. What is the name of this iconic South American liberator?",
            "answers": ["Simon Bolivar"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This site served as the busiest immigrant inspection station in the United States from 1892 to 1954. It processed approximately 12 million immigrants who entered the country. The island was expanded from its original size using land reclamation, largely due to the surplus earth from the construction of the New York City subway system. Today, it is part of the Statue of Liberty National Monument and houses a museum that explores immigrant experiences. What is the name of this island, once known as the \"Gateway to America\"?",
            "answers": ["Ellis Island"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Born Peter Gene Hernandez, this American artist made a splash with his debut album \"Doo-Wops & Hooligans\" in 2010, featuring hits like \"Just the Way You Are\" and \"Grenade.\" Known for his vibrant performances and retro flair, he has won multiple Grammy Awards and achieved international fame with songs such as \"Uptown Funk\" with Mark Ronson. Celebrated for blending pop, R&B, funk, and soul, what is the stage name of this dynamic performer?",
            "answers": ["Bruno Mars"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This university located in Manhattan, New York is led by Minouche Shafik. Established in 1754 as King's College on the grounds of Trinity Church, it is the oldest institution of higher education in New York and the fifth-oldest in the United States. Name this university that made headlines in April 2024 after pro-Gaza protests created an encampment on its campus and occupied a university building.",
            "answers": ["Columbia"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American former professional boxer emerged as the undisputed heavyweight champion of the world in the late 1980s. His quick ascension to the top included becoming the youngest boxer ever to win a heavyweight title at just 20 years old. Known for his powerful punches and controversial moments both inside and outside the ring, his career features significant bouts including a highly publicized match where he was disqualified for biting an opponent's ear. What is the name of this iconic boxer, often referred to by his nickname \"Iron Mike\"?",
            "answers": ["Mike Tyson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This Russian chemist created a systematic table in the late 19th century, organizing elements by atomic mass and chemical properties. His work predicted the properties of elements before they were discovered and has been fundamental to the development of chemical science. Known for this significant contribution to chemistry, what is the name of the scientist who developed the Periodic Table?",
            "answers": ["Dmitri Mendeleev", "Mendeleev"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Emerging as a prominent figure in college football, this quarterback started his career at the University of Oklahoma. He quickly made headlines during his freshman year before transferring to USC, where he continued to excel and won the Heisman Trophy in 2022. In 2024 he was selected as the first pick in the NFL Draft by the Chicago Bears. What is the name of this rising star in the sport?",
            "answers": ["Caleb Williams"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This reality television series, which first aired in 2002, features a single man starting with a pool of romantic interests from whom he is expected to select a wife. Over multiple weeks, he dates the candidates, with eliminations based on rose ceremonies, leading to home visits and ultimately, marriage proposals. Known for its dramatic rose ceremonies and often controversial outcomes, this show has spawned numerous spin-offs and international versions. What is the name of this long-running series that has become a cultural phenomenon in the realm of dating shows?",
            "answers": ["The Bachelor"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This figure rose to power after leading a successful revolution in 1959 that overthrew the Batista regime. His policies transformed his nation into the first communist state in the Western Hemisphere. His tenure was marked by significant tensions with the United States, including the infamous Bay of Pigs Invasion and the Cuban Missile Crisis. Known for his long speeches and iconic military-style attire, he remained a controversial global figure until his death in 2016. Who is this revolutionary leader?",
            "answers": ["Fidel Castro"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American figure has made a significant impact both as a professional wrestler and as an actor. Known for his time in WWE, where his catchphrase \"You can't see me\" became iconic, he has won multiple championships and is recognized for his charismatic persona and philanthropy, especially his record number of wishes granted for the Make-A-Wish Foundation. Transitioning into acting, he has appeared in films like \"Trainwreck\" and \"Bumblebee,\" showcasing his versatility beyond the ring. What is the name of this influential entertainer who has successfully crossed over from sports entertainment to mainstream cinema?",
            "answers": ["John Cena"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Organized by Elizabeth Cady Stanton and Lucretia Mott, this 1848 gathering marked the beginning of the organized women's suffrage movement in America. It took place in a small New York town and produced a pivotal document known as the Declaration of Sentiments, which asserted the equality of men and women and demanded women's suffrage among other rights. What is the name of this historic convention?",
            "answers": ["Seneca Falls Convention", "Seneca Falls"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered by Alexander Fleming in 1928, this substance marked the beginning of the antibiotic era, revolutionizing the treatment of bacterial infections. Derived from the Penicillium mold, it was the first antibiotic to successfully combat diseases such as syphilis, gangrene, and tuberculosis. Its development significantly decreased the death rate in World War II by treating infected wounds. What is the name of this groundbreaking antibiotic?",
            "answers": ["Penicillin"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known for its profound influence on classical music, this capital city has been home to legendary composers such as Mozart, Beethoven, and Schubert. Renowned for its architectural beauty, it features iconic structures like the Sch\u00f6nbrunn Palace and St. Stephen's Cathedral. Additionally, this city is famous for its historic coffee house culture, which has been recognized by UNESCO as an intangible cultural heritage. What is the name of this culturally rich European city?",
            "answers": ["Vienna Austria", "Vienna"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This epic poem details the protagonist's ten-year journey home to Ithaca after the fall of Troy, where he encounters numerous obstacles including the Cyclops, the Sirens, and the wrath of Poseidon. Meanwhile, his wife, Penelope, and son, Telemachus, deal with suitors attempting to take over his kingdom. This work attributed to the ancient Greek poet Homer, a sequel to \"The Iliad,\" is considered a seminal piece in Western literature. What is the name of this classic narrative?",
            "answers": ["The Odyssey"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This major Christian holiday marks the culmination of the Passion of Christ, preceded by Lent, a 40-day period of fasting, prayer, and penance. Its date varies each year, determined by the lunar calendar to fall on the first Sunday after the first full moon occurring on or after the vernal equinox. Celebrated with traditions such as egg hunts and a festive bunny, it commemorates a pivotal event: the resurrection of Jesus Christ. What is the name of this holiday?",
            "answers": ["Easter"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This pivotal document took effect on January 1, 1863. It declared that all enslaved people in Confederate-held territory were to be set free, fundamentally shifting the war\u2019s focus to include the abolition of slavery as a Union goal alongside reunification. Although it didn\u2019t immediately free all slaves, it was a crucial step towards the abolition of slavery and paved the way for the Thirteenth Amendment. What is the name of this historic proclamation?",
            "answers": ["Emancipation Proclamation"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Nestled between the imposing Table Mountain and the confluence of the Atlantic and Indian Oceans, this city is known for its stunning natural landscapes and vibrant cultural scene. It is one of South Africa's three capital cities, specifically serving as the legislative center. Notable landmarks include the historic Robben Island, where Nelson Mandela was imprisoned, and the colorful houses of the Bo-Kaap district. What is the name of this picturesque city at the southern tip of Africa?",
            "answers": ["Cape Town", "Cape Town South Africa"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Beginning in 1789, this pivotal event marked a period of radical social and political upheaval in a large European nation. It led to the downfall of the monarchy, rise of the Republic, and a series of successive revolutionary governments. Key symbols include the storming of the Bastille and the adoption of the Declaration of the Rights of Man and of the Citizen. What is the name of this historic period in French history?",
            "answers": ["French Revolution"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This former professional cyclist became famous worldwide for winning the Tour de France seven consecutive times from 1999 to 2005, a feat unmatched in the history of the sport. However, his career later became overshadowed by one of the most significant doping scandals in sports, leading to his titles being stripped and his being banned from competitive cycling for life. Known for his cancer survival and founding of a cancer support foundation, what is the name of this controversial athlete?",
            "answers": ["Lance Armstrong"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Launched by NASA in the late 1970s, these twin spacecraft were designed to explore the outer planets and then continue on to study the outer limits of the Sun's influence. Their missions have provided humanity with close-up photos of Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune, vastly expanding our knowledge of these systems and the outer solar system. Remarkably, both probes have now entered interstellar space, sending back valuable data about the heliosphere and beyond. What is the collective name of these pioneering space probes?",
            "answers": ["Voyager"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Written when the author was just 16 years old and published in 1967, this novel is a pivotal piece of adolescent literature that captures the intense class struggles between two rival groups, the Greasers and the Socs, in 1960s Oklahoma. The story is told through the perspective of Ponyboy Curtis, a young Greaser who navigates the challenges of violence, class conflict, and growing up. What is the title of this influential novel by S.E. Hinton?",
            "answers": ["The Outsiders"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1986, this groundbreaking music video features a blend of claymation, pixilation, and stop-motion animation, creating a visually stunning and innovative experience. It was made for a song by Peter Gabriel and won a record nine MTV Video Music Awards, a record that still stands. The video is often celebrated for its creativity and technical achievements in animation, helping to set a new standard for the art form in the music industry. What is the name of this iconic music video, known for its pioneering visual effects and animation techniques?",
            "answers": ["Sledgehammer"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This Russian opposition leader and anti-corruption activist was known for his vocal criticism of the Kremlin and President Vladimir Putin. He organized large-scale demonstrations and utilized social media and YouTube to expose corruption and mobilize public dissent. In 2020, he was the victim of a high-profile poisoning attack, which he survived and attributed to Russian government agents. What is the name of this prominent figure in contemporary Russian politics who died in 2024 after being confined in a Russian prison since 2021?",
            "answers": ["Alexey Navalny"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known for its rich history that traces back to the Aztec Empire, this city features landmark sites like the Z\u00f3calo plaza and the ancient ruins of Tenochtitl\u00e1n. It boasts an impressive array of museums, including the Frida Kahlo Museum and the National Museum of Anthropology, and is celebrated for its culinary delights, particularly tacos and tamales. Serving as the capital of Mexico, what is the name of this vibrant metropolitan area?",
            "answers": ["Mexico City", "Mexico DF"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This American political figure represented West Virginia in the U.S. Senate for over 51 years, making him the longest-serving Senator in history. Initially elected to the House of Representatives in 1952 and then to the Senate in 1958, he held his Senate seat until his death in 2010. Early in his career, he was a member of the Ku Klux Klan, a fact he later said he regretted and spent much of his career attempting to atone for. He also served as the Senate Majority Leader at various times during the 1970s and 1980s. What is the name of this influential senator?",
            "answers": ["Robert Byrd"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Initiated by the February Revolution which led to the abdication of Tsar Nicholas II, this transformative period in 1917 resulted in major political upheaval. The Bolsheviks, led by Lenin, seized power in the subsequent October Revolution, marking the rise of the Soviet Union and the end of the Romanov dynasty. This series of events significantly impacted global politics throughout the 20th century. What is the name of this pivotal period in Russian history?",
            "answers": ["Russian Revolution"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This private aerospace manufacturer and space transport services company, established in 2002, has been a pioneer in the development of reusable rockets. Among its achievements are being the first privately funded entity to send a liquid-fueled rocket to orbit, successfully launch, orbit, and recover a spacecraft, and dispatch astronauts to the International Space Station. Founded with the ultimate goal of enabling Mars colonization, it was started by entrepreneur Elon Musk. What is the name of this company known for revolutionizing space travel?",
            "answers": ["SpaceX"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Established in 1933, this professional American football team is part of the AFC North division in the NFL and is known for its deep-rooted history and passionate fan base. Holding the record for the most Super Bowl titles tied with another franchise, they are renowned for their tough, physical style of play. Famous for their black and gold colors, they play their home games at Acrisure Stadium, where fans are known for waving the iconic \"Terrible Towel.\" What is the name of this team, based in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania?",
            "answers": ["Pittsburgh Steelers", "Steelers"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This American novelist is renowned for her powerful narratives that explore the African American experience.  In 1993, she became the first African American woman to win the Nobel Prize in Literature, celebrated for her epic themes and vivid dialogue. She won the Pulitzer Prize for her novel \"Beloved\" in 1988, a story about a mother and her daughter dealing with the haunting legacy of slavery. Her works often focus on issues of identity, race, and humanity. What is the name of this influential literary figure?",
            "answers": ["Toni Morrison"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1939, this epic historical romance is set in the American South during the Civil War and Reconstruction era. It follows the turbulent life of Scarlett O'Hara, the spirited daughter of a plantation owner, and her romantic entanglements with Ashley Wilkes and Rhett Butler. Known for its sweeping narrative and complex characters, this film won multiple Academy Awards, including Best Picture. It remains one of the highest-grossing films of all time when adjusted for inflation. What is the title of this classic film, famous for its line, \"Frankly, my dear, I don't give a damn\"?",
            "answers": ["Gone with the Wind"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Debuting in 2007, this reality television series provides an intimate look into the lives of a high-profile family, chronicling their personal and professional dramas. Known for its influence on pop culture and social media, the show features sisters Kim, Khlo\u00e9, and Kourtney, along with their half-sisters Kendall and Kylie. It has spawned numerous spin-offs and remained a staple in reality TV for over a decade. What is the name of this long-running series that tracks the day-to-day activities of the Kardashian-Jenner family?",
            "answers": ["Keeping Up with the Kardashians", "Kardashians"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This former NFL wide receiver largely played for the Minnesota Vikings and New England Patriots. Known for his impressive vertical leap and speed, he set the single-season touchdown reception record as a rookie in 1998 and later broke his own record in 2007 with 23 touchdown receptions. What is the name of this Hall of Fame wide receiver known for setting remarkable receiving records?",
            "answers": ["Randy Moss"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Founded in 2006, this American social media platform is known for its microblogging service where users post and interact with messages. It has played a significant role in social movements and public discourse worldwide. In 2022 Elon Musk purchased this company and has since renamed it to \"X\". What is the name of this influential social media company which previously featured a blue bird in its logo?",
            "answers": ["Twitter", "X", "Twitter"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This battle featured significant engagements at locations like Little Round Top and Pickett's Charge. This 1863 battle was the conflict with the largest number of casualties in the U.S. Known as the turning point of the Civil War, it concluded with President Abraham Lincoln's famous address, which redefined the purpose of the war. Located in a small town in Pennsylvania, this battle marked a decisive defeat for the Confederacy. What is the name of this historic battle?",
            "answers": ["Battle of Gettysburg", "Gettysburg"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This 20th century Colombian author is known for his seminal works in the magical realism genre. He was awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature in 1982 for his novels and short stories that combine the fantastic with the realistic in a richly composed world of imagination. His novel \"One Hundred Years of Solitude\" is acclaimed globally, weaving intricate family sagas with fantastical elements to reflect the political and social realities of Latin America. What is the name of this influential literary figure?",
            "answers": ["Gabriel Garc\u00eda M\u00e1rquez"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This scientific theory describes the large-scale motions of Earth's lithosphere, which is divided into several plates that glide over the mantle. Proposed in the early 20th century and gaining wide acceptance by the 1960s, this theory explains many aspects of geological phenomena, including earthquakes, volcanic activity, and continental drift. It also helps scientists understand the formation of mountain ranges and ocean trenches. What is the name of this fundamental theory that explains the dynamic nature of Earth's surface?",
            "answers": ["Plate Tectonics", "tectonics", "tectonic plates"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "The first of these conflicts between China and Britain ended in 1842 with the Treaty of Nanking, and resulted in Hong Kong's cession to Britain and the opening of several Chinese ports to foreign merchants. The second war, from 1856 to 1860 and involving France alongside Britain, further expanded port access and led to significant treaty concessions. Central to the conflicts was the controversial trade of a narcotic substance. What is the collective term for these conflicts, named after the substance at their heart?",
            "answers": ["Opium Wars"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Historically, this desert has been the habitat for nomadic Bedouin tribes, adapting to life in these challenging conditions. Covering much of the Arabian Peninsula, this desert is one of the largest continuous sand deserts in the world. It features a harsh, arid climate with sand dunes that can reach significant heights. The area is known for its extreme temperatures, which can plummet at night after soaring during the day. What is the name of this expansive desert region?",
            "answers": ["The Arabian Desert", "Arabian"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This medieval ruler, known as the \"Father of Europe,\" was king of the Franks and later crowned Emperor of the Romans, a title that revitalized the concept of a united Western Europe since the fall of the Roman Empire. His reign, beginning in the late 8th century, was marked by numerous military campaigns that expanded his kingdom to cover much of Western and Central Europe. He was a patron of the arts and education, initiating what would later be called the Carolingian Renaissance, a period of cultural and intellectual revival. What is the name of this emperor who significantly shaped European history and laid the foundations for modern European states?",
            "answers": ["Charlemagne"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Founded in 1899, this esteemed football club from Spain, is celebrated for its rich history, distinctive blue and garnet striped jerseys, and a philosophy deeply rooted in attractive, attacking football. Known for their motto \"M\u00e9s que un club\" (More than a club), they are a symbol of Catalan pride and culture. The club has achieved immense success both domestically and internationally, including 27 La Liga titles and 5 UEFA Champions League trophies. Their storied rivalry with Real Madrid in \"El Clasico\" is watched by millions around the world. What is the name of this iconic football club, famous for its youth academy, La Masia, which has produced many top-class players including Lionel Messi?",
            "answers": ["FC Barcelona", "Barcelona"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Known for his reassuring statement during America's Great Depression, \"The only thing we have to fear is fear itself,\" this influential American politician served as the 32nd President of the United States from 1933 until his death in 1945. He introduced the New Deal to combat the economic crisis and led the country through most of World War II, famously collaborating with Britain and the Soviet Union as part of the Allies. Holding office longer than any other U.S. president, he was also renowned for his fireside chats that bolstered national morale. What is the name of this president?",
            "answers": [
                "Franklin Delano Roosevelt",
                "FDR",
                "Franklin Roosevelt"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This platform was originally named A.me but now goes by the name Douyin in China. It was released outside of China in September 2017 and merged with the app Musical.ly in 2018. The app now has over a billion users. It is owned by the Chinese company ByteDance and has come under scrutiny for connections with China's Communist Party. This trend-setting app allows users to share short form video content. Name this app which is the subject of legislation saying it must be sold to a U.S. based company or face a national ban.",
            "answers": ["TikTok"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This surrealist painting is famed for its striking and bizarre images of soft, melting pocket watches. It depicts a dream-like scene in which time appears fluid and warped, reflecting the artist's interpretation of the relativity of space and time. The setting includes a desolate landscape that enhances the ethereal and surreal quality of the work. Created by Salvador Dal\u00ed in 1931, it is often seen as a symbol of the irrationality of the human mind, this painting is one of the most recognizable pieces of surrealist art. What is the name of this influential painting by Dal\u00ed, known for its unique interpretation of time?",
            "answers": ["Persistence of Memory"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known as the \"Land of 10,000 Lakes,\" this U.S. state is famous for its multitude of lakes and the scenic wilderness of its northern regions, including the Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness. It is also home to the Mall of America, one of the largest shopping malls in the country, located in Bloomington. The state's vibrant cultural life is highlighted by the twin cities of Minneapolis and St. Paul, the latter serving as the state capital. What is the name of this northern state?",
            "answers": ["Minnesota"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered in 1868 during a solar eclipse, this element is the second lightest and second most abundant in the observable universe, primarily formed from the nuclear fusion of hydrogen in stars. It is colorless, odorless, and inert, making it useful in cryogenics, particularly in the cooling of superconducting magnets, with applications in MRI scanners and NMR spectrometers. Unlike other gases, it does not solidify at standard atmospheric pressure, remaining a liquid down to absolute zero under normal conditions. What is the name of this noble gas, known for causing balloons to float when filled with it?",
            "answers": ["Helium"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1967, this groundbreaking album by the British band The Beatles is often hailed as one of the greatest albums of all time. Known for its innovative production, complex music arrangements, and an eclectic mixture of musical styles, it marked a significant departure from the band's earlier pop sound. The album's cover, featuring the Beatles in colorful military-style costumes amid a collage of famous faces, has become iconic. It includes hits such as \"Lucy in the Sky with Diamonds\" and \"A Day in the Life.\" What is the name of this influential Beatles album that is celebrated for its pioneering approach to studio recording?",
            "answers": [
                "Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band",
                "sergeant pepper",
                "sergeant pepper's lonely hearts club band",
                "st pepper"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Held annually on the first Monday of May, this prestigious event is a major fundraising gala for the Costume Institute at the Metropolitan Museum of Art in New York City. Known for its exclusive guest list, extravagant outfits, and often provocative themes, it marks the opening of the Costume Institute's annual fashion exhibit. Each year, celebrities and designers collaborate to create elaborate fashion statements that align with the theme of the exhibit, making it one of the most notable nights in fashion. What is the name of this glamorous event, often dubbed as \"fashion's biggest night out\"?",
            "answers": ["Met Gala"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This influential U.S. president is known for his call to action, \"Ask not what your country can do for you\u2014ask what you can do for your country\"? He was instrumental in pivotal events such as the Cuban Missile Crisis, the advancement of the Civil Rights Movement, and the initiation of the Apollo space program. This man served as the 35th President of the United States from 1961 until his assassination in 1963. Name this President whose term was tragically cut short in Dallas, Texas. ",
            "answers": ["John F Kennedy", "JFK", "J.F.K."],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This spiral galaxy, named after the constellation in which it resides, is the nearest major galaxy to the Milky Way and the largest galaxy in our local group. Approximately 2.5 million light-years away from Earth, it is on a collision course with our galaxy, with an expected merger occurring in about 4.5 billion years. Known for its bright appearance and visible to the naked eye under dark skies, this galaxy offers a glimpse into the dynamics of galaxy formation and evolution. What is the name of this galaxy, often studied for its proximity and similarities to our own Milky Way?",
            "answers": ["Andromeda", "andromena"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "First published in 1866, this seminal Russian novel delves into the moral dilemmas of Rodion Raskolnikov, a former student living in St. Petersburg who commits a murder under the pretense of a philosophical theory. The narrative explores his psychological turmoil and the ensuing consequences of his actions, addressing deep questions about morality, guilt, and redemption. Set against the backdrop of a grim 19th-century Russia, this work is celebrated for its psychological depth and its profound exploration of existential despair. What is the title of this classic novel written by Fyodor Dostoevsky that challenges the notion of moral justifiability of crime?",
            "answers": ["Crime and Punishment"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Premiering in 2002, this critically acclaimed television series created by David Simon offers a gritty, realistic exploration of life in Baltimore, Maryland. The show extends over five seasons, each focusing on a different facet of the city from the drug trade and the port system to the city government and schools. The show featured characters called Omar and Stringer played by Michael Kenneth Williams and Idris Elba respectively. What is the name of this TV show renowned for its in-depth look at the interconnectedness of society\u2019s different layers?",
            "answers": ["The Wire"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Russian tsar, known for his extensive reforms aimed at modernizing Russia, ruled from the late 17th century into the early 18th century. His efforts to transform Russian society included the introduction of Western technologies and industries, the reorganization of the Russian military, and the establishment of a new capital, St. Petersburg, which was intended to serve as a \"window to the West.\" What is the name of this towering figure in Russian history, celebrated for his drive to establish Russia as a major European power?",
            "answers": ["Peter the Great"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This professional ice hockey team joined the NHL in 1967 as part of the league's expansion. Known for their black and gold colors, they have won 5 Stanley Cup championships, largely due to the contributions of legendary players like Mario Lemieux and Sidney Crosby. The team has a passionate fan base and plays its home games at PPG Paints Arena. Their successful periods in the early 1990s and late 2000s to early 2010s have cemented their status as a dominant force in the NHL. What is the name of this NHL franchise based in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, renowned for its resilience and championship pedigree?",
            "answers": ["Pittsburgh Penguins", "Penguins"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This U.S. state, one of the original Thirteen Colonies, is located in the northeastern region known as New England. It has a significant place in early American history, often referred to by its nickname \"The Constitution State,\" due to its Fundamental Orders of 1638-1639, considered by some as the first written constitution that created a government. Known for its blend of coastal cities and rural areas dotted with small towns, it has a strong maritime tradition and is a leader in industries such as finance and insurance. What is the name of this state, home to the prestigious Yale University and recognized for its high standard of living?",
            "answers": ["Connecticut"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Created by Norwegian artist Edvard Munch in 1893, this expressionist painting is known for its intense and emotional depiction of a figure against a blood-red sky. The central figure is portrayed in a moment of existential angst and despair, with an agonized expression that has become iconic. The background of a tumultuous sky over a blue-black fjord adds to the drama of the scene. This artwork is widely recognized as a symbol of human anxiety. What is the name of this powerful painting that captures a profound sense of dread and perception of the modern world?",
            "answers": ["The Scream"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "In 1804, these two explorers embarked on a historic expedition commissioned by President Thomas Jefferson following the Louisiana Purchase. Their journey aimed to map the newly acquired territories, establish trade with Native American tribes, and find a practical route across the western half of the continent to the Pacific Ocean. Assisted significantly by Sacagawea, a Lemhi Shoshone woman, they provided valuable geographical and scientific data that contributed to the expansion of the United States. What is the collective name of this duo known for their pioneering expedition to the western United States?",
            "answers": [
                "Lewis & Clark",
                "Lewis and Clark",
                "Lewis and Clark expedition",
                "Corps of Discovery Expedition"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "During this player's illustrious NHL career, which spanned from 1979 to 1999, he set records that still stand, including most points in a season and most career goals, assists, and points. He won four Stanley Cups with the Edmonton Oilers in the 1980s and earned the Hart Trophy as the league's most valuable player an unprecedented nine times. His number, 99, has been retired across the NHL in his honor. Known as \"The Great One,\" this Canadian athlete is widely considered the greatest hockey player of all time. What is the name of this legendary ice hockey player whose exceptional skill and sportsmanship elevated the entire sport?",
            "answers": ["Wayne Gretsky"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This organization was founded by Ahmed Yassin in 1987 after the outbreak of the First Intifada against the Israeli occupation. The group was designated as a terrorist organisation in 1995 by the United States. In 2006 the group won the Palestinian legislative election and has governed the Israeli-occupied Gaza Strip since 2007. The group made headlines in 2023 for carrying out terrorist attacks and kidnapping individuals in Israel on October 7. Name this organization whose attack started a hot war between this organization and the Israeli government.",
            "answers": ["Hamas"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This U.S. state, one of the original Thirteen Colonies, played a significant role in the American Revolution and was the first state to secede from the Union in the lead-up to the Civil War. Known for its subtropical beaches and marshlike sea islands, it is also home to historic cities like Charleston, famous for its well-preserved architecture and rich history as a major slave trading port. The state's economy historically relied on agriculture, but has diversified into manufacturing and tourism. What is the name of this state, also noted for being the site of the first shots fired in the Civil War at Fort Sumter?",
            "answers": ["South Carolina"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Debuting in 1989, this animated sitcom created by Matt Groening is set in the fictional town of Springfield and follows the lives of a family. Known for its satirical take on American culture, society, television, and many aspects of the human condition, it has become one of the longest-running shows in television history. The series is celebrated for its colorful array of characters and clever humor. What is the name of this iconic TV show that features the characters Homer, Marge, Bart, Lisa, and Maggie?",
            "answers": ["The Simpsons"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Macedonian king, born in 356 BC, was one of history\u2019s most successful military commanders. By the age of 30, he had created one of the largest empires of the ancient world, stretching from Greece to northwestern India. He was never defeated in battle, leveraging his formidable tactical abilities and the military innovations of the Macedonian phalanx. His legacy includes the spread of Greek culture and language across the territories he conquered, significantly influencing subsequent cultural and historical developments. What is the name of this legendary conqueror known for founding over twenty cities that bore his name, the most famous being Alexandria in Egypt?",
            "answers": [
                "Alexander The Great",
                "Alexander",
                "Alexander III of Macedon"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This prominent star, known for its distinct reddish hue, is one of the largest and brightest in the night sky, forming the shoulder of the constellation Orion. Classified as a red supergiant, it is nearing the end of its life cycle, with astronomers predicting that it will eventually explode in a supernova. Located approximately 642 light-years from Earth, it is one of the best examples of a star in the late stages of stellar evolution, providing valuable insights into the life cycles of massive stars. What is the name of this star, famous for its size, brightness, and position in one of the most recognizable constellations?",
            "answers": ["Betelgeuse", "beatlejuice", "beetle juice"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1994 and based on Stephen King's novella, this film follows Andy Dufresne, a banker wrongfully imprisoned for murder in Shawshank State Penitentiary. Over decades, he forms a significant friendship with fellow inmate, Ellis \"Red\" Redding, as they endure the hardships of incarceration. Directed by Frank Darabont, the movie explores profound themes of hope and redemption and has become one of the most revered films in cinema history. What is the title of this film, celebrated for its enduring message that \"hope is a good thing, maybe the best of things, and no good thing ever dies\"?",
            "answers": ["The Shawshank Redemption"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered in 1789 by German chemist Martin Heinrich Klaproth, who named it after a planet, this element is notable for its radioactive properties and heavy atomic weight. It plays a crucial role in nuclear power generation and as the primary material for nuclear weapons. This element's most common isotope, numbered 238, has a half-life of about 4.5 billion years, making it useful in dating the age of the Earth. It is also dense enough to be used in military armor and high-density projectiles. What is the name of this radioactive element named after Uranus that has had significant implications for both energy production and weaponry?",
            "answers": ["Uranium"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Commissioned in 1632 by the Mughal emperor Shah Jahan to house the tomb of his favorite wife this iconic mausoleum stands as a symbol of eternal love and is one of the most recognized buildings in the world. Located in Agra, India, it is renowned for its stunning white marble architecture and intricate craftsmanship involving inlaid semiprecious stones and carvings. This UNESCO World Heritage site attracts millions of visitors annually and is celebrated for its majestic presence and aesthetic beauty. What is the name of this famous structure, often described as \"a teardrop on the cheek of time\"?",
            "answers": ["Taj Mahal"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Roman general and statesman played a crucial role in the events that led to the demise of the Roman Republic and the rise of the Roman Empire. Known for his pivotal part in the Gallic Wars, he subsequently became a dictator in perpetuity, a title he held until his assassination in 44 BC. His death on the Ides of March marked a turning point that led to the rise of his adopted heir, Augustus, and the establishment of the Roman Empire. What is the name of this historical figure, famous for his declaration \"Veni, Vidi, Vici\" after a swift victory at the Battle of Zela?",
            "answers": ["Julius Caesar"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NBA team gained international fame in the 1990s due to its extraordinary success, including winning six NBA championships between 1991 and 1998. This era of dominance was largely driven by the presence of Michael Jordan, one of basketball's all-time greats, along with key figures like Scottie Pippen and coach Phil Jackson. Known for their iconic red, black, and white uniforms, the team's legacy includes setting an NBA record for most wins in a regular season, a record they held until 2016. What is the name of Chicago's NBA franchise, synonymous with 1990s basketball dominance?",
            "answers": ["Chicago Bulls", "Bulls"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This prominent American patriot was the President of the Continental Congress. A wealthy merchant and smuggler prior to the American Revolution, he used his resources to support the colonial cause and later served as the governor of Massachusetts. His prominent and stylish autograph became so iconic that his name is now synonymous with the word \"signature.\" What is the name of this influential figure whose signature is one of the most recognized in American history?",
            "answers": ["John Hancock"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "First held in 1929, this annual event honors outstanding achievements in the film industry, making it the most prominent and prestigious awards ceremony in Hollywood. Organized by the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, it celebrates excellence in cinematic achievements as assessed by the Academy's voting membership. Known for its red carpet and the iconic golden statuette, the event brings together the biggest names in entertainment. What is the name of this ceremony that serves as the pinnacle of recognition for film achievements?",
            "answers": ["Oscars", "Academy Awards", "the oscars"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This southern nation has 11 official languages, reflecting its multicultural heritage. The nation's rich history includes significant archaeological sites like the Cradle of Humankind, where some of the oldest hominid fossils have been found. The country is also famed for its wildlife and conservation areas such as the Kruger National Park. It transitioned from a system of apartheid to a democracy in the 1990s under the leadership of Nelson Mandela, its first black president. What is the name of this country, characterized by its complex history and natural beauty?",
            "answers": ["South Africa"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Premiering in 1951, this iconic American television sitcom stars Lucille Ball and her real-life husband, Desi Arnaz. The show follows the comedic antics of a housewife with dreams of stardom, and her bandleader husband, Ricky, as they navigate life in New York City. Known for its pioneering use of the three-camera setup and live audience format, it became famous for its timeless humor and is credited with setting the standard for sitcoms that followed. What is the name of this groundbreaking series, celebrated for episodes like \"Lucy Does a TV Commercial\"?",
            "answers": ["I Love Lucy"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Portuguese footballer is renowned for his exceptional skill and athleticism on the pitch, making him one of the most celebrated players in the sport's history. Known for his prolific goal-scoring abilities, he has won multiple FIFA Ballon d'Or awards and has played for top European clubs including Sporting Lisbon, Manchester United, Real Madrid, and Juventus. His remarkable career is also highlighted by numerous UEFA Champions League titles and a significant impact in international play, leading Portugal to victory in the 2016 UEFA European Championship. What is the name of this iconic forward, often considered one of the greatest footballers of all time?",
            "answers": ["Cristiano Ronaldo", "Ronaldo"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Constructed during the Great Depression between 1931 and 1936, this massive concrete arch-gravity dam is located on the border between Arizona and Nevada in the Black Canyon of the Colorado River. Originally known as the Boulder Dam, it was later renamed to honor the man who was the President when the construction started. Today, it is also a major tourist attraction, known for its impressive engineering and historical significance. What is the name of this dam?",
            "answers": ["Hoover Dam"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Located in Central America, this country is known for its rich Mayan heritage, evident in the famous ruins of Tikal, and a diverse landscape that includes rainforests, volcanoes, and mountainous regions. It was once the heart of the Maya civilization, which flourished until the early 16th century. After centuries as a Spanish colony, it gained independence in 1821. Today, it is celebrated for its vibrant indigenous cultures, colorful textile crafts, and a cuisine that blends Spanish and Mayan influences. What is the name of this nation, bordered by Mexico to the north and west, Belize to the northeast, and Honduras and El Salvador to the southeast?",
            "answers": ["Guatemala"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Known as \"The Most Exciting Two Minutes in Sports,\" this prestigious horse race is held annually on the first Saturday in May. Established in 1875, it is the longest-running sporting event in the United States. The race is the first leg of the American Triple Crown, followed by the Preakness Stakes and the Belmont Stakes. It's celebrated with a festival that includes mint juleps, big hats, and the singing of \"My Old Kentucky Home.\" What is the name of this famous race that takes place at Churchill Downs and is a pinnacle of thoroughbred horse racing?",
            "answers": ["Kentucky Derby"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This English monarch, reigning in the early 16th century, is perhaps best known for his six marriages and the drastic measures he took to secure a male heir, which included breaking away from the Roman Catholic Church to establish the Church of England. His split from the Vatican led to the English Reformation, a series of events that significantly altered the religious landscape of England. His reign also saw the dissolution of the monasteries, which redistributed wealth and land from the church to the Crown and nobles. What is the name of this king whose personal and political decisions had a profound impact on English history?",
            "answers": ["Henry VIII", "Henry the eighth"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Woven with intricate detail and extensive lore, this seminal high-fantasy series by J.R.R. Tolkien features the quest to destroy a powerful artifact that epitomizes the potential for both good and evil. The narrative unfolds across a vast, fictional realm known as Middle-earth, where diverse races and languages enrich the complex history of its world. Lauded for its deep exploration of themes such as sacrifice, courage, and the persistent battle against malevolence, the trilogy includes the novels \"The Fellowship of the Ring,\" \"The Two Towers,\" and \"The Return of the King.\" What is the title of this epic literary work that has profoundly influenced the fantasy genre?",
            "answers": ["Lord of the Rings"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Developed by Albert Einstein in 1905, this theory revolutionized physics by introducing new concepts about time and space. It posits that the laws of physics are the same for all non-accelerating observers and that the speed of light within a vacuum is the same no matter the speed at which an observer travels. A key implication of this theory is that time can dilate, or slow down, and lengths can contract depending on the relative speed of objects in motion. What is the name of this groundbreaking theory that fundamentally altered our understanding of how the universe operates?",
            "answers": ["Special Relativity", "Relativity"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered in 1898 by Scottish chemist William Ramsay and English chemist Morris Travers in the residue left over from evaporating components of liquid air, this element is a colorless, dense, odorless noble gas used in a variety of applications. It is employed in flash lamps and arc lamps for photography, and its isotopes are used in the medical field for imaging and anesthesia. Additionally, it is used in ion propulsion systems for spacecraft. Known for its rarity and heavy atomic weight among the noble gases, what is the name of this element that also features prominently in high-performance light-emitting devices and medical imaging?",
            "answers": ["Xenon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This queen of Castile and Le\u00f3n, reigning in the late 15th century alongside her husband Ferdinand of Aragon, is best known for her role in the Reconquista, the completion of which was marked by the conquest of Granada in 1492. Her reign significantly advanced the unification of Spain and the Spanish Inquisition, which aimed to consolidate Catholic orthodoxy within her kingdoms. She also famously sponsored Christopher Columbus's 1492 voyage, which led to the European discovery of the New World. What is the name of this influential monarch?",
            "answers": [
                "Isabella of Spain",
                "Isabella the Catholic",
                "Queen Isabella",
                "Isabella"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1941, this landmark American film, directed by and starring Orson Welles, is frequently lauded as one of the greatest movies of all time. Known for its innovative use of deep focus cinematography, narrative structure, and special effects, the film tells the complex story of a wealthy newspaper magnate inspired by the life of William Randolph Hearst. Its narrative unfolds through a series of flashbacks following a reporter's quest to decipher the meaning behind the magnate's mysterious last word, \"Rosebud.\" What is the title of this influential film that revolutionized the techniques of filmmaking and narrative construction in cinema?",
            "answers": ["Citizen Kane"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Renowned as one of the greatest American architects of the 20th century, this visionary created designs that harmonized with humanity and its environment, a philosophy he called organic architecture. Notable for his innovative work, he designed over 1,000 structures during his career, which emphasized simplicity and natural beauty, fundamentally changing how we think about spaces. His most famous works include Fallingwater in Pennsylvania and the Guggenheim Museum in New York. What is the name of this architect known for his unique approach to building design, which seamlessly integrates the elements of human habitation with the natural surroundings?",
            "answers": ["Frank Lloyd Wright"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This professional football player was selected by the Kansas City Chiefs in the third round of the 2013 NFL Draft out of University of Cincinnati. He recently signed a contract making him the highest paid tight end in the NFL after winning Super Bowl LVIII. He is a cohost of the New Heights podcast with his brother Jason. Name this player who who made headlines for being in a relationship with the pop star Taylor Swift during the last NFL season.",
            "answers": ["Travis Kelce"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "First held in 1911, this iconic automobile race is known as \"The Greatest Spectacle in Racing.\" The race is traditionally run over the Memorial Day weekend and is famous for its 200 laps around a 2.5-mile oval track, totaling 500 miles. It is one of the three events that make up the Triple Crown of Motorsport, which also includes the Monaco Grand Prix and the 24 Hours of Le Mans. What is the name of this renowned race held annually at the Indianapolis Motor Speedway and celebrated for its high speeds and challenging conditions?",
            "answers": ["Indianapolis 500", "Indie 500", "indy 500"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This U.S. state, known for its vast wilderness and sparse population, was purchased from Russia in 1867 in a deal often referred to as \"Seward's Folly.\"  Rich in natural resources, it is a major hub for energy production, particularly oil and natural gas. The state's stunning landscapes, including Denali National Park and the Inside Passage, are major attractions, as well as its abundant wildlife. It is the largest state in the U.S. by area but one of the least densely populated. What is the name of this state, famous for phenomena like the Northern Lights and the Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race?",
            "answers": ["Alaska"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Launched in the 1930s in response to the Great Depression, this series of economic and social reforms included the creation of agencies like the Works Progress Administration (WPA) and the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC), which provided employment through public works projects. It also introduced significant financial reforms and established the Social Security system to aid the elderly and unemployed. Initiated by President Franklin D. Roosevelt, this initiative aimed to restore prosperity and dignity to Americans during a time of economic crisis. What is the name of this pivotal economic recovery initiative?",
            "answers": ["New Deal"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This U.S. state, admitted to the Union in 1896 as the 45th state, is known for its diverse landscapes ranging from arid deserts with sand dunes to thriving pine forests in mountain valleys. It is renowned for its natural beauty, including national parks like Zion, Arches, and Bryce Canyon, which offer spectacular red rock formations. The state is also a center for outdoor recreational activities, including skiing, which was prominently featured during the 2002 Winter Olympics held near its capital. What is the name of this state, also known for its significant Mormon community?",
            "answers": ["Utah"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Before entering politics, this individual gained fame as a comedian and actor, notably starring in a television show where he played the role of the President of Ukraine. Mirroring his on-screen persona, he ran for the actual presidency and was elected in 2019 with a campaign that promised to tackle corruption and bring peace to the eastern regions of Ukraine, where conflict with separatists had been ongoing. Since then, he has become a prominent figure internationally, especially noted for his leadership during Ukraine's war with Russia. What is the name of this Ukrainian president known for his role as the head of the warring nation?",
            "answers": ["Volodomyr Zelensky"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This figure was the first emperor of Rome, marking the transition from the Roman Republic to the Roman Empire following the tumultuous period of civil wars that ensued after Julius Caesar's assassination. Known originally as Octavian, he was Caesar's adopted son and heir. He reigned from 27 BC until his death in AD 14, establishing a period of relative peace known as the Pax Romana that lasted over two centuries. What is the name of this emperor, celebrated for founding the Roman Empire and inaugurating an era of relative peace and prosperity?",
            "answers": [
                "Augustus",
                "Octavius Caesar",
                "Octavius",
                "Gaius Octavius",
                "Octavian"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This radioactive metallic element was first produced and isolated in 1940 by a team led by Glenn T. Seaborg and Edwin McMillan at the University of California, Berkeley, by bombarding uranium with deuterons. It is used primarily in nuclear reactors and nuclear weapons, notably in the \"Fat Man\" type bombs dropped on Nagasaki in 1945. Highly reactive, it has several isotopes, the most significant being numbered 239, known for its ability to sustain a nuclear chain reaction. What is the name of this element, named after the dwarf planet Pluto, critical to the development of atomic energy and weaponry?",
            "answers": ["Plutonium"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This American Founding Father is known for his diplomatic efforts during the Revolutionary War when he helped negotiate the Treaty of Paris, which officially ended the war. Additionally, his correspondence with his wife, Abigail, provides an invaluable insight into the era's political and social dynamics. Name this man who was a key figure in drafting The Declaration of Independence, served as the first Vice President of the United States, and later served as the second President.",
            "answers": ["John Adams"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This iconic artwork was completed in 1908 during the high point of the artist's \"Golden Phase.\" It depicts a couple embraced in an ornate, golden swirl of robes, blending elements of Art Nouveau and the Byzantine influence that the Austrian Symbolist painter Gustav Klimt admired. The painting is celebrated for its luxurious use of gold leaf and its sensual portrayal of intimacy and love. Displayed in the \u00d6sterreichische Galerie Belvedere museum in Vienna, it remains one of Klimt's most famous and adored works. What is the title of this masterpiece known for its lavish and emotive representation of a couple's embrace?",
            "answers": ["The Kiss"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Debuting in 1999, this groundbreaking television series is credited with initiating the era of prestige TV, featuring complex characters, intricate plots, and psychological depth rarely seen before in the medium. It centers on a New Jersey mob boss as he struggles to manage the dual responsibilities of his criminal organization and his family life, often discussing these challenges with his therapist. The show blends dark humor with dramatic elements and has been lauded for its deep exploration of issues such as mental health, family dynamics, and the American dream. What is the name of this critically acclaimed series that many consider to be one of the greatest TV shows of all time?",
            "answers": ["The Sopranos"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American gymnast, celebrated for revolutionizing her sport, has won a record-breaking 25 World Championship medals and 7 Olympic medals. Known for her extraordinary skill and athleticism, she dominated the gymnastics scene, securing individual all-around, vault, and floor exercise titles multiple times. She has also contributed several unique skills to the sport, with moves named after her in three apparatuses, showcasing her innovative techniques. Beyond her competitive achievements, she has become a vocal advocate for athletes' mental health. What is the name of this iconic gymnast, known for setting new records and standards in gymnastics?",
            "answers": ["Simone Biles"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American Football team is known for their dynastic run in the early 21st century, when they claimed multiple Super Bowl titles, largely under the leadership of head coach Bill Belichick and quarterback Tom Brady. Based in Foxborough, Massachusetts, this team has become one of the most successful franchises in NFL history with 6 Super Bowl titles. What is the name of this NFL team, noted for its distinctive navy blue, red, and silver uniforms and a strong legacy of championships?",
            "answers": ["New England Patriots", "Patriots"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This red dwarf star is part of the Alpha Centauri star system, located in the constellation of Centaurus. Discovered in 1915 by Scottish astronomer Robert Innes, it is situated approximately 4.24 light-years away from Earth making it the closest known star to the Sun. Despite its proximity, it is too faint to be seen with the naked eye. Notably, in 2016, astronomers discovered an Earth-sized exoplanet in its habitable zone, raising questions about potential life. What is the name of this star, the nearest known neighbor to our solar system?",
            "answers": ["Proxima Centauri", "Alpha Centauri C"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Founded in the early 19th century as a colony for freed American and Caribbean slaves, this West African nation declared its independence in 1847, making it the first democratic republic in African history to gain its independence without a revolution. Its capital, Monrovia, is named after James Monroe, a U.S. President who supported the colonization process. The country has faced significant challenges in recent decades, including two civil wars and the Ebola outbreak, but has been working towards reconciliation and development. What is the name of this country, unique for its historical ties to the United States?",
            "answers": ["Liberia"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1939 and based on L. Frank Baum's novel, this beloved musical film follows Dorothy Gale, a young girl from Kansas who is swept away by a tornado to the magical land of Oz. There, she embarks on a journey to see the Wizard in hopes of returning home, accompanied by her dog Toto and new friends\u2014the Scarecrow, the Tin Man, and the Cowardly Lion. Known for its iconic songs, Technicolor cinematography, and memorable characters, the film has become a cornerstone of American pop culture. What is the title of this classic movie that famously features the song \"Somewhere Over the Rainbow\"?",
            "answers": ["The Wizard of Oz"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Created by the Italian artist Sandro Botticelli in the mid-1480s, this renowned Renaissance painting depicts the goddess Venus emerging from the sea as a fully grown woman, according to classical mythology. The work is celebrated for its grace and beauty, illustrating the idealized human form in harmony with nature. It features Venus standing on a giant shell, being blown towards shore by the winds, personified by Zephyr. Displayed in the Uffizi Gallery in Florence, this artwork remains a quintessential example of Renaissance art's fascination with classical mythology. What is the name of this famous painting that captures the mythological birth of the goddess of love and beauty?",
            "answers": ["The Birth of Venus"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This American statesman and writer became the 26th President of the United States, known for his exuberant personality and range of interests. Coming to office after the assassination of President William McKinley in 1901, he promoted progressive policies that emphasized anti-trust actions and conservation efforts, founding numerous national parks and forests. He was also a key figure in negotiating the end of the Russo-Japanese War, for which he was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize. Notably, he is one of the four presidents featured on Mount Rushmore. What is the name of this dynamic leader who championed the \"Square Deal\"?",
            "answers": ["Theodore Roosvelt", "Teddy Roosevelt"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This king, reigning in the early 5th century, is noted for founding the Merovingian dynasty, which would rule the Frankish kingdom for nearly 300 years. His conversion to Christianity\u2014specifically to the Roman Catholic creed\u2014was a pivotal event, influencing many of his Frankish warriors to follow suit, thus strengthening alliances with Roman Christian churches. This decision had profound implications for the religious landscape of medieval Europe, helping to solidify Catholicism in the region. What is the name of this king, credited with uniting various Frankish tribes under one rule and shaping the future religious and political structure of Western Europe?",
            "answers": ["Clovis", "clovis I"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This militant group, originating in the early 1990s in Afghanistan, emerged from the chaos following the Soviet-Afghan War, drawing members largely from Afghan refugees educated in religious schools in Pakistan. They took control of Afghanistan in 1996 and imposed strict interpretations of Islamic law, leading to widespread human rights criticisms, especially regarding the treatment of women. After being ousted from power in 2001 by U.S.-led forces, they waged an insurgency and regained control in 2021 following the withdrawal of foreign troops. What is the name of this group, known for its fundamentalist policies and governance of Afghanistan?",
            "answers": ["Taliban", "The Taliban"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This monarch, known as the \"Sun King,\" reigned over France for 72 years, making his tenure one of the longest in European history. Ascending to the throne in the mid-17th century, he is best known for his autocratic regime that firmly established the absolute power of the monarchy. His reign saw the construction of the Palace of Versailles, a symbol of royal extravagance and absolutism. He also fostered a flourishing of arts and culture that made France the center of intellectual and artistic life in Europe. What is the name of this French king, under whose rule France became the leading European power?",
            "answers": ["Louis XIV", "Louis the fourteenth", "King Louis"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "First held in 1903, this annual championship series is often referred to as the \"Fall Classic\". It is one of the most watched sporting events in the U.S., known for creating legends and memorable moments in baseball history. The series has seen numerous iconic teams, including the New York Yankees, who hold the record for the most titles. It is the culmination of the Major League Baseball season in the United States, featuring a best-of-seven playoff between the champions of the National League and the American League. What is the name of this prestigious event in baseball?",
            "answers": ["World Series", "The World Series"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1974, this film is both a sequel and a prequel to its predecessor, expanding on the saga of the Corleone family by depicting the early life and career of Vito Corleone in 1920s New York and his son Michael's expansion and tightening grip on the family crime syndicate during the 1950s. Directed by Francis Ford Coppola, it is noted for its rich storytelling and complex portrayal of the transformation of its characters, particularly Michael Corleone's descent into corruption and moral decay. The movie received critical acclaim and multiple Academy Awards, including Best Picture. What is the title of this acclaimed sequel that explores themes of power, family, and betrayal in the American Mafia?",
            "answers": [
                "The Godfather Part II",
                "The Godfather 2",
                "Godfather II"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This U.S. state, located in the Western region, is best known for its expansive deserts and as the leading silver producer in the country, which earned it the nickname \"The Silver State.\" The state also features significant natural beauty, such as the Sierra Nevada mountains and Great Basin National Park. It is also famed for its liberal laws on gambling and entertainment, with Las Vegas, known as the entertainment capital of the world, drawing millions of tourists annually. What is the name of this state, which became the 36th state to join the Union in 1864 and is known for its vibrant nightlife and historic mining towns?",
            "answers": ["Nevada"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This President is known for his ambitious domestic policies including the \"Great Society\" program, which aimed to eliminate poverty and racial injustice. His administration significantly expanded civil rights, public broadcasting, Medicare, Medicaid, aid to education, and the arts. However, his presidency was also marked by the escalation of the Vietnam War, which overshadowed his substantial legislative achievements. What is the name of this U.S. president who became the 36th President of the United States following the assassination of President John F. Kennedy in 1963?",
            "answers": ["Lyndon B Johnson", "LBJ", "L.B.J"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This is the brightest star in the constellation Ursa Minor and has been used for navigation and orientation for centuries, including by sailors and explorers to determine latitude. This star, also known as the North Star, holds a crucial position almost directly above the North Pole, making it an excellent fixed point for navigation in the Northern Hemisphere.  It is actually a triple star system, consisting of the main supergiant star and two smaller companions. What is the name of this star that is famous for its steadfast position in the sky, guiding travelers throughout history?",
            "answers": ["Polaris"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This executive became CEO of The Walt Disney Company in 2005, overseeing a significant expansion of its global entertainment operations. Under his leadership, the company acquired Pixar, Marvel, Lucasfilm, and 21st Century Fox, significantly broadening its film and television content. He also spearheaded the launch of Disney+, a direct-to-consumer streaming service that competes with other major platforms. Known for his strategic vision and leadership, he played a key role in making Disney a dominant force in the entertainment industry. What is the name of this influential business leader who helped shape the modern landscape of media and entertainment?",
            "answers": ["Bob Iger", "Iger"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This iconic bronze sculpture depicts a life-sized figure deep in thought. Originally part of a larger work called \"The Gates of Hell,\" it represents Dante pondering his great poem, \"The Divine Comedy.\" Over time, the figure has come to symbolize philosophical thinking and introspection more broadly. Versions of this famous work originally created by the French artist Auguste Rodin in 1904, can be found in numerous museums around the world, making it one of the most recognized sculptures in modern art. What is the name of this renowned sculpture, celebrated for its portrayal of contemplation and intellectual engagement?",
            "answers": ["The Thinker"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This American technology entrepreneur co-founded a major social media platform while attending Harvard University in 2004. The platform quickly exploded in popularity, redefining global communication and eventually attracting billions of users worldwide, influencing various aspects of society, from business to politics. Known for his role in the development and expansion of social networking, he has also faced significant scrutiny and controversy over privacy issues and the platform's role in disseminating information. What is the name of this influential figure, the CEO of Facebook, who became one of the world's youngest billionaires?",
            "answers": ["Mark Zuckerberg"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NBA franchise, established in 1946, is one of the league's most storied teams. The team has a fierce rivalry with the Los Angeles Lakers, contributing to several epic matchups in NBA Finals history. The team's legacy includes a record-setting number of NBA Championships and a host of Hall of Fame players such as Bill Russell, Larry Bird, and Paul Pierce. Known for their distinctive green and white uniforms, they are a symbol of basketball excellence and tradition. What is the name of Boston's NBA team, famous for its historical success and contributions to basketball lore?",
            "answers": ["Boston Celtics", "Celtics"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This U.S. state, known as the \"Land of Enchantment,\" joined the Union in 1912 as the 47th state. It is renowned for its diverse landscape, which includes desert, mesa, and mountain territories, and a rich blend of Native American and Hispanic cultures, reflected in its art, architecture, and cuisine. The state has a strong scientific community, evidenced by institutions like Los Alamos National Laboratory, where the atomic bomb was developed. It is also famous for hosting the largest hot air balloon festival in the world. What is the name of this state, distinguished by its significant contributions to both nuclear research and cultural heritage?",
            "answers": ["New Mexico"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This film was released in 1994 and directed by Quentin Tarantino. The narrative intertwines the lives of two mob hitmen, a boxer, a gangster's wife, and a pair of diner bandits, exploring themes of redemption and violence in a stylized manner. The movie's structure is a pastiche of various genres, making it a defining example of postmodern cinema. It was a major critical and commercial success, revitalizing the careers of several of its stars, including John Travolta. What is the title of this influential film that features the iconic dance scene between Travolta and Uma Thurman?",
            "answers": ["Pulp Fiction"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This critical biological process involves the conversion of atmospheric nitrogen gas into a form that is usable by living organisms, primarily ammonia. It is carried out by certain types of bacteria, some of which live in a symbiotic relationship with the root nodules of leguminous plants. This natural conversion is essential for building amino acids and proteins, thereby playing a key role in the nitrogen cycle that supports the growth of many forms of life on Earth. What is the term for this process that allows nitrogen, an element vital for life, to be absorbed by plants and enter the food chain?",
            "answers": ["Nitrogen fixation"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This famous painting was created by Dutch artist Johannes Vermeer around 1665. Known for its subtle use of light and shadow, this work is often referred to as the \"Mona Lisa of the North\" due to its enigmatic expression and the mysterious allure of its subject. The artwork belongs to the collection of the Mauritshuis museum in The Hague and continues to intrigue art lovers with its simple yet profound beauty. What is the name of this celebrated painting that portrays a young girl looking over her shoulder, adorned with a striking pearl earring?",
            "answers": ["Girl with a Pearl Earring"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This 18th-century Prussian king is celebrated for his military prowess and enlightened domestic policies. Ascending to the throne in 1740, he expanded Prussian territories through his adept handling of the military during the Silesian Wars and the larger conflict of the Seven Years' War, establishing Prussia as a significant European power. Known for his patronage of the arts and philosophy, he also promoted reforms that made his kingdom a cultural beacon in the Age of Enlightenment. What is the name of this ruler, often referred to as an archetype of the enlightened despot?",
            "answers": ["Frederick the Great", " Frederick II", "Frederick"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This American polymath and  Founding Fathers was instrumental in drafting the Declaration of Independence and the U.S. Constitution. A noted inventor, he created the lightning rod and bifocal glasses. His experiments with electricity were groundbreaking, contributing significantly to the scientific understanding of the time. Also a diplomat, he played a crucial role in securing French support during the American Revolution. What is the name of this influential figure, who also established Philadelphia\u2019s first fire department and library?",
            "answers": ["Benjamin Franklin", "Ben Franklin"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered and isolated by Scottish physician Daniel Rutherford in 1772, this diatomic gas constitutes about 78% of the Earth's atmosphere and is essential for all living organisms, being a primary component of amino acids in proteins. It is also utilized in various industrial processes, such as ammonia production and as a coolant for sensitive equipment. What is the name of this colorless, odorless element that is the most abundant in our atmosphere?",
            "answers": ["Nitrogen"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This surprise double album broke Spotify's single-day streaming record upon release. It explores its author's psyche and personal experiences, and features collaborations with Jack Antonoff and Aaron Dessner. It is the eleventh studio album by an acclaimed singer-songwriter who recently embarked on her Eras Tour. This album was released on April 19, 2024 and contains 31 songs across two volumes. What is the title of this record-breaking release by Taylor Swift?",
            "answers": [
                "The Tortured Poets Department",
                "dead poets department"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Forming the northern boundary of the Pacific Ring of Fire, this chain of islands is noted for its active volcanoes and rugged terrain. The archipelago has historical significance due to battles fought on its soil during World War II\u2014the only such battles on U.S. soil against Japan. Additionally, these islands play a crucial role in the migratory paths of various marine animals and host a unique blend of wildlife. Stretching from the Alaskan Peninsula to Russia, what is the name of this island chain?",
            "answers": ["The Aleutian Islands", "Aleutian Islands"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This island was the site of a prominent Native American protest from 1969 to 1971, highlighting Indigenous rights. Before that in 1934, it was converted into a federal prison designed to detain the most troublesome inmates, including notable figures like Al Capone and the \"Birdman\" Robert Stroud.  Managed by the National Park Service, this island attracts over a million visitors each year and is known for its historic lighthouse and military prison facilities. What is this island, often referred to as \"The Rock,\" located in San Francisco Bay?",
            "answers": ["Alcatraz"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This battle is famously depicted in the Bayeux Tapestry, which chronicles the events leading up to and including this historical clash. In 1066, this decisive battle changed the course of English history when William the Conqueror, the Duke of Normandy, defeated King Harold II. This victory led to the Norman conquest of England, significantly influencing the English language, culture, and legal system. What is the name of this pivotal battle that established Norman rule in England?",
            "answers": ["Battle of Hastings"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Serbian tennis player has made a significant impact on the sport, consistently ranking among the world's top players since turning professional in 2003. Known for his exceptional athleticism and mental toughness, he has won numerous Grand Slam titles, holding records for the most Australian Open wins. His rivalry with contemporaries like Roger Federer and Rafael Nadal has been a defining feature of his career, contributing to what many consider the golden era of tennis. What is the name of this elite tennis player known for dominating the modern era of tennis?",
            "answers": ["Novak Djokovic"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This 2019 blockbuster is the culmination of over a decade of Marvel Cinematic Universe films, bringing together a vast array of characters to face the formidable villain Thanos in a final showdown. It follows the dramatic events of \"Avengers: Infinity War,\" where many heroes vanished due to Thanos' actions. Known for its epic battles and time-traveling narrative, it became the highest-grossing film of all time until 2021. What is the title of this Marvel Studios movie that serves as a grand finale to its first saga of films?",
            "answers": ["Avengers: Endgame", "endgame"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Composed in Iceland during the 13th century by the historian, poet, and politician Snorri Sturluson, this collection of Old Norse poems and tales is a primary source for modern knowledge of Norse mythology. It serves not only as a manual for aspiring poets, describing the poetic meter of the time, but also details the mythology and stories that were foundational to Norse culture, including the creation of the world and the tales of gods like Odin and Thor. What is the name of this crucial text that preserves much of what we know about Norse mythology and medieval Scandinavian literature?",
            "answers": ["The Prose Edda", "prose edda"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Coined by Mark Twain, this term describes a period in U.S. history from the 1870s to about 1900, marked by rapid industrialization and economic growth, alongside stark income inequality and political corruption. Notable figures like John D. Rockefeller and Andrew Carnegie amassed fortunes, while the railroads, steel, and oil industries boomed. Despite its prosperous facade, the era was rife with underlying social issues. What is the name of this period in American history?",
            "answers": ["Gilded Age"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This rebellion was initiated by a secret society known for practicing martial arts, and the movement aimed to oust imperialist foreigners and restore Chinese sovereignty. The rebellion resulted in the Eight-Nation Alliance invading Beijing to suppress the uprising and relieve besieged foreign embassies. The aftermath included harsh reparations imposed on China, exacerbating the decline of the Qing Dynasty. What is the name this violent anti-foreign and anti-Christian uprising which occurred in China between 1899 and 1901?",
            "answers": [
                "Boxer Rebellion",
                "Boxer Uprising",
                "Boxer Insurrection",
                "Yihetuan Movement"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered first in 1940 by chemists Glenn T. Seaborg, Edwin McMillan, Joseph W. Kennedy, and Arthur Wahl, these synthetic elements are produced artificially in nuclear reactors or particle accelerators. With atomic numbers greater than 92, which is that of uranium, they are not found naturally. This group includes well-known elements such as neptunium and plutonium. What is the collective term for these artificially created elements?",
            "answers": ["Transuranium Elements", "Transuranium"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Known for his remarkable longevity and performance in the NFL, this quarterback has won seven Super Bowl titles, more than any other player in league history. He spent the first 20 seasons of his career with the New England Patriots, where he became synonymous with the team's dynasty, before moving to the Tampa Bay Buccaneers and securing another championship. Renowned for his precision passing and clutch performances in critical moments, he has secured multiple MVP awards and numerous Super Bowl MVP titles. What is the name of this iconic football player?",
            "answers": ["Tom Brady"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Founded in 2003, this American company is named after a Serbian-American inventor and is known for its innovative electric vehicles and renewable energy products. Under the leadership of its prominent CEO, it became the first electric car manufacturer to produce a fully electric luxury sedan, the Model S, which has received numerous awards for safety and performance. This company introduced the \"Cybertruck\" and hopes to one day have autonomous taxis. Name this company led by Elon Musk.",
            "answers": ["Tesla"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known for its modern skyline dominated by the iconic Petronas Twin Towers, once the tallest buildings in the world, this city is a cultural melting pot with a diverse culinary scene and vibrant neighborhoods like Chinatown and Little India. It's also a major global tourism and retail hub, featuring numerous shopping districts and hosting an iconic Fashion Week. Serving as the capital of Malaysia, what is the name of this bustling metropolis in Southeast Asia?",
            "answers": ["Kuala Lumpur", "KL"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This iconic television series, which first aired in 1989, became famous for its scenes of lifeguards patrolling the sunny beaches of California. Known for its red swimsuits and slow-motion running shots, the show focused on the personal and professional lives of a team of lifeguards led by the character Mitch Buchannon. It gained international fame, becoming one of the most watched TV shows globally during the 1990s. What is the name of this series that became synonymous with beach lifeguard drama?",
            "answers": ["Baywatch"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Emerging in the late 16th century in Italy and spreading across Europe, this architectural style is characterized by its dramatic use of light and shadow, expansive ornate structures, and a focus on motion and emotion. Notable for its intricate details and grandeur, it often features large-scale ceiling frescoes, twisted columns, and extensive use of gold. Key examples include the Palace of Versailles in France and St. Peter's Basilica in Rome. What is the name of this exuberant style that dominated European architecture and art through the 17th and early 18th centuries?",
            "answers": ["Baroque"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This iconic American singer, songwriter, and dancer first gained fame as a member of the Jackson 5 and then soared to unprecedented heights with his solo career. His 1982 album featured hits like \"Billie Jean\" and \"Beat It.\" He won numerous Grammy Awards throughout his career, including a record-breaking eight Grammys in one night for \"Thriller.\" What is the name of this legendary entertainer often referred to as the \"King of Pop\"?",
            "answers": ["Michael Jackson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This British writer and scholar, born in 1898, was a noted Christian apologist and a member of the Inklings, a literary discussion group at Oxford, alongside J.R.R. Tolkien. He used his academic background in literature to explore and defend his faith through works like \"Mere Christianity.\" He is best known for creating \"The Chronicles of Narnia,\" a series of seven beloved fantasy novels. What is the name of this influential author and theologian?",
            "answers": ["C.S. Lewis", " CS Lewis"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This Jewish holiday commemorates the Biblical story of Exodus, where Hebrew slaves were freed from bondage in Egypt. According to the narrative, the Israelites were instructed to mark the doorposts of their homes with the blood of a slaughtered spring lamb so that the spirit of the Lord knew to pass over these homes, hence the name of the holiday. Traditionally observed for eight days by many Jewish communities, it involves rituals such as the Seder meal, which includes reading from the Haggadah, eating matzah, and other symbolic foods. What is the name of this holiday that begins on the 15th of the Hebrew month of Nissan?",
            "answers": ["Passover"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Spanning several countries in southern Africa, this vast semi-arid sandy savanna is known for its red sand, sparse vegetation, and diverse wildlife, including meerkats and the famous black-maned lions. Despite its dry conditions, it supports more animal and plant life than a true desert. The region is also home to the indigenous San people, who have adapted traditional techniques to survive its harsh environment. What is the name of this desert that stretches across Botswana, parts of Namibia, and South Africa?",
            "answers": ["The Kalahari Desert", "Kalahari"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Belgian former professional cyclist, often hailed as the most accomplished rider in the history of the sport, won the Tour de France five times during his career in the late 1960s and early 1970s. His dominance extended beyond France into the Giro d'Italia, which he also won five times, and he achieved a record 34 stage wins in the Tour de France. Known for his nickname \"The Cannibal\" due to his relentless competitive drive, what is the name of this legendary cyclist?",
            "answers": ["Eddy Merckx"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Initiated by the Latin Church in the medieval period, these campaigns aimed to reclaim Jerusalem and other holy lands from Muslim control, beginning in the late 11th century and lasting until the late 13th century. Over time, the objectives expanded to encompass various political, economic, and territorial motives. Significantly shaping Christian and Muslim relations, these events had a profound impact on the geography and politics of the Middle East. What is the general term for these historical campaigns?",
            "answers": ["The Crusades", "Crusades"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Triggered by various events such as undersea earthquakes, volcanic eruptions, underwater landslides, or meteorite impacts, these high-energy sea waves can cause catastrophic damage when they reach coastal areas. Notably, the 2004 Indian Ocean event highlighted the critical need for early warning systems to prevent disasters. What is the term used to describe these powerful series of ocean waves?",
            "answers": ["Tsunami"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This project was initiated in response to fears that Nazi Germany would develop nuclear weapons first. It began in 1942 and involved some of the greatest scientific minds of the time, including Robert Oppenheimer and Enrico Fermi. It led to the development and testing of the first nuclear weapons in Los Alamos, New Mexico. The culmination of this project was the dropping of atomic bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki in 1945, significantly impacting the conclusion of World War II. What is the name of this pivotal scientific and military project?",
            "answers": ["Manhattan project"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This Nobel laureate, who adopted a pen name to avoid conflict with his father, became a senator for the Chilean Communist Party. Renowned for his passionate love poems and odes to ordinary objects, his most famous collection, \"Twenty Love Poems and a Song of Despair,\" was published in his youth. He later served as a diplomat in various countries, writing the poem \"I Explain a Few Things\" during the Spanish Civil War.",
            "answers": ["Pablo Neruda"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "At the age of 14, this Romanian gymnast made history at the 1976 Montreal Olympics by becoming the first gymnast to score a perfect 10.0 in an Olympic event, a feat she achieved not once, but seven times throughout the competition. Her flawless routines on the uneven bars and balance beam earned her three gold medals, including the prestigious all-around title. Name this gymnast who added two more gold medals in the 1980 Olympics.",
            "answers": ["Nadia Comaneci"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This U.S. Senator and his wife, Nadine, are currently facing trial for bribery charges over alleged gifts from Egyptian and Qatari nationals in exchange for favorable treatment. In 2015 this same Senator was charged in a separate corruption case which eventually ended when the charges were dropped in 2018. This Democrat is the senior Senator from New Jersey, serving since 2006. Name this politician who chaired the Committee on Foreign relations from 2013-2015 and 2021-2023.",
            "answers": ["Bob Menendez", " Robert Menendez"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This transcontinental city straddles the Bosphorus Strait, a natural waterway that serves as a boundary between two continents. Its strategic location has made it a coveted prize throughout history, leading to its role as the capital of both the Byzantine and Ottoman Empires. Historically known as Byzantium and Constantinople, a blend of Eastern and Western influences is evident in its architecture, cuisine, and culture. Which city, the largest in Turkey, is the only metropolis in the world situated on two continents?",
            "answers": ["Istanbul"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This American president had a centrist political philosophy which became known as the \"Third Way\". He was the first president born in the Baby Boomer generation and participated in the Camp David Summit to advance the Israeli\u2013Palestinian peace process. He was twice elected governor of Arkansas and defeated George H.W. Bush and Bob Dole as he was elected President twice. Name this 42nd President who married Hillary Rodham.",
            "answers": ["Bill Clinton"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This science fiction franchise, despite initial cancellation after three seasons, gained a cult following through syndicated reruns and spawned a media empire. It premiered in 1966 with a multiracial crew led by Captain James T. Kirk aboard the USS Enterprise. Its creator, Gene Roddenberry, envisioned a future where humanity united to explore the galaxy. The show's original mission was \"to explore strange new worlds, to seek out new life and new civilizations, to boldly go where no man has gone before.\"",
            "answers": ["Star Trek"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This British politician and writer served as First Lord of the Admiralty during World War I but was demoted after the disastrous Gallipoli Campaign. He is most known for his wartime leadership during World War II, where he delivered powerful speeches, including \"We shall fight on the beaches.\" He earned a Nobel Prize in Literature in 1953 for books he wrote about his WWII experiences. Name this British statesman who served two terms as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom and who coined the phrase \"Iron Curtain\" in a famous speech.",
            "answers": ["Winston Churchill"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This international scientific research project was declared essentially complete in 2003, with 92% of human DNA sequenced. A working draft was announced in 2000, a significant milestone in the project's timeline. Led by an international consortium of scientists, it involved mapping and deciphering the 3 billion base pairs that make up human DNA. This ambitious endeavor sought to map and understand all the genes of human beings. What was the name of this project, which has since revolutionized fields from medicine to forensics?",
            "answers": ["Human Genome Project", "Genome", "Human Genome"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Prussian statesman, born into the Junker nobility, orchestrated the unification of Germany in 1871 through a series of strategic wars, including victories over Austria and France. This man served as the first Chancellor of the German Empire from 1871 to 1890, and became known as the \"Iron Chancellor\". Who is this leader known for his strong leadership and Realpolitik approach to politics?",
            "answers": ["Otto Von Bismark"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Constructed on an artificial island at the entrance of Charleston Harbor in South Carolina, this masonry fort was named for a Revolutionary War hero  It was designed to protect the harbor from naval attacks and became a focal point of tension between the Union and the Confederacy in the lead-up to the Civil War. Following South Carolina's secession from the Union in December 1860, the fort's commander, Major Robert Anderson, refused to surrender it to Confederate authorities, leading to a bombardment that marked the official beginning of the Civil War in April 1861.",
            "answers": ["Fort Sumter"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This British actress and fashion icon, known for her roles in classic films during Hollywood's Golden Age, epitomized elegance and charm with her performances in \"Breakfast at Tiffany's,\" \"Roman Holiday,\" for which she won an Academy Award, and \"My Fair Lady.\" Beyond her film career, she was also celebrated for her humanitarian work with UNICEF. Her style and grace left a lasting impression on the fashion and film industries. What is the name of this beloved actress and philanthropist, renowned for both her distinctive cinematic roles and her dedication to charity?",
            "answers": ["Audrey Hepburn"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This single-stranded molecule, essential for protein synthesis, comes in three main types: messenger, transfer, and ribosomal. It carries genetic code from DNA, delivers amino acids to the ribosome, and forms a key component of ribosomes. Which molecule, found in all living cells and some viruses, serves as a vital link between genetic information and protein production, making it indispensable for life?",
            "answers": ["RNA", "Ribonucleic Acid"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This athlete was the first player in NCAA history to lead the nation in both points and assists in a single season. She was named the consensus National Player of the Year in 2023, winning the Naismith Trophy, the Wade Trophy, and the Wooden Award. She led her team to the NCAA championship game in 2023, where they lost to LSU. Name this Iowa Hawkeyes star who was selected as the first overall pick in the 2024 WNBA draft by the Indiana Fever.",
            "answers": ["Caitlin Clark"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This playwright, who married Marilyn Monroe in 1956, was once blacklisted by the House Un-American Activities Committee for refusing to name suspected communists. He is celebrated for his powerful portrayals of American life and social injustice, particularly in plays exploring themes of guilt, responsibility, and the American Dream. Two of his most notable works include \"The Crucible,\" a drama about the Salem witch trials that serves as an allegory for McCarthyism, and \"Death of a Salesman,\" a tragedy about a struggling salesman who grapples with disillusionment and failure.",
            "answers": ["Arthur Miller"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This historic city, located in the \u00cele-de-France region, lies within a basin on the Seine River, approximately 233 miles from its mouth on the English Channel. Its urban landscape is characterized by wide boulevards and a harmonious blend of Haussmannian architecture and iconic landmarks like the Eiffel Tower and Arc de Triomphe. The city is divided into 20 arrondissements, spiraling outward from the historic center on the \u00cele de la Cit\u00e9. Which city, renowned for its art, fashion, and cuisine, serves as the capital of France and a global center of culture?",
            "answers": ["Paris", "Paris, France"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Spanish football club is one of the most successful and popular sports teams globally. Founded in 1902, it has won numerous domestic league titles and holds the record for the most UEFA Champions League victories. Known for their iconic white kits, the club has a storied history featuring legendary players such as Alfredo Di Stefano, Cristiano Ronaldo, and Zinedine Zidane. Their intense rivalry with FC Barcelona, known as \"El Clasico,\" is one of the most famous in sports. What is the name of this football club, renowned for its rich history and success in both national and international competitions?",
            "answers": ["Real Madrid"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "The series finale of this coming-of-age sitcom aired on May 16, 2024 on CBS after seven seasons. This show, filmed in front of a live studio audience, follows the life of a child prodigy in East Texas. The show was gained a surprising new fan base when it was released on Netflix in Fall 2021. Name this CBS sitcom that is narrated by Jim Parsons and follows the early life of Parsons's character previously featured in the hit show \"The Big Bang Theory.\"",
            "answers": ["Young Sheldon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This revolutionary, born Ioseb Besarionis dze Jughashvili, adopted a pseudonym meaning \"man of steel.\" He orchestrated the Great Purge, a period of political repression and executions. His Five-Year Plans aimed to rapidly industrialize the Soviet Union. As General Secretary of the Communist Party, he led the Soviet Union during World War II and the beginning of the Cold War. Name this Soviet leader.",
            "answers": ["Victor Stalin", "Stalin"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "An engineering student at Oregon State University, this athlete struggled to master the straddle and western roll high jump techniques. After experimenting with unconventional methods, he developed a revolutionary back-first technique that he unveiled at the 1968 Mexico City Olympics. Despite initial skepticism, this technique propelled him to a gold medal and quickly became the dominant style in high jump, which now bears his name followed by an alliterative \"Flop.\"",
            "answers": ["Dick Fosbury"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This cellular structure, a network of interconnected membranous sacs and tubules, plays a crucial role in protein and lipid synthesis. It is divided into two distinct regions: rough, studded with ribosomes and involved in protein production and folding, and smooth, lacking ribosomes and responsible for lipid metabolism and detoxification. Found in all eukaryotic cells, its expansive surface area facilitates its diverse functions. What is the name of this organelle, often referred to as the \"highway\" of the cell due to its role in transporting molecules?",
            "answers": ["Endoplastmic Reticulum", "E.R.", "ER"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Emerging in neutral Switzerland during World War I as a reaction against the war's violence and nationalism, this artistic and literary movement embraced chaos, irrationality, and nonsense. It challenged traditional notions of art and aesthetics, employing techniques like collage, photomontage, and readymades. The name of this movement, possibly chosen at random from a dictionary, is often associated with anti-establishment sentiments. What is the name of this movement whose prominent figures included Tristan Tzara, Marcel Duchamp, and Hugo Ball?",
            "answers": ["Dadaism", "Dada"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "A staunch advocate for democracy, this U.S. president was the first to hold a Ph.D. and taught political science at Princeton University before entering politics. He led the nation through World War I, coining the phrase \"The world must be made safe for democracy.\" However, his dream of establishing the League of Nations faced opposition in Congress, and his health suffered a severe blow when he experienced a debilitating stroke in 1919. Who was this 28th President of the United States who envisioned a new world order after the Great War?",
            "answers": ["Woodrow Wilson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This island city-state, located at the southern tip of the Malay Peninsula, consists of one main island and 62 smaller islets. It is separated from Malaysia by the Johor Strait and from Indonesia by a strait which shares its name. Despite its small size of approximately 734 square kilometers, it is a global financial hub and a major shipping center, boasting the world's busiest transshipment port. Its diverse population comprises predominantly Chinese, Malay, and Indian ethnic groups. Which city-state, known for its cleanliness, efficiency, and strict laws, is a popular destination for both business and leisure travelers?",
            "answers": ["Singapore"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This popular sitcom, filmed in black and white for its first five seasons, was a spin-off of \"The Danny Thomas Show.\" Set in the fictional town of Mayberry, North Carolina, it followed the life of a widowed sheriff, his son, and his bumbling deputy. The show's gentle humor, heartwarming storylines, and memorable characters like Aunt Bee, Gomer Pyle, and Floyd the Barber made it a beloved classic, ranking among the most-watched shows from 1960-1968. Name this iconic comedy series starring Andy Griffith, Ron Howard, and Don Knotts.",
            "answers": ["The Andy Griffith Show", "Andy Griffith"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Born James Cleveland in Oakville, Alabama, this athlete moved to Cleveland, Ohio at age nine. He won four gold medals at the 1936 Berlin Olympics in the 100 meters, 200 meters, long jump, and 4x100 meter relay. His victories challenged Adolf Hitler's propaganda about Aryan racial superiority, as he set Olympic records in the long jump and 200 meters and equaled the world record in the 100 meters. Name this American Olympic icon.",
            "answers": ["Jesse Owens"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "In the 1960s, Canadian scientists Ernest A. McCulloch and James E. Till made a groundbreaking discovery of these cells in mouse bone marrow. Classified into two main types, embryonic and adult, they offer vast potential in regenerative medicine, but also raise ethical concerns, especially with embryonic sources. Their unique ability to differentiate into specialized cells has led to promising research in treating diseases like Parkinson's and diabetes. What are these cells, hailed as a potential breakthrough in medicine yet also the subject of ongoing ethical discussions?",
            "answers": ["Stem Cells"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This European nation established a colony in 1908 which encompassed a vast territory in Central Africa rich in natural resources such as rubber, ivory, and minerals. It gained notoriety for the harsh treatment of the indigenous population under the rule of King Leopold II, leading to international condemnation and a humanitarian crisis. The colonial region ultimately achieved independence in from this nation in 1960, adopting the name Republic of the Congo before later changing it. Name the European nation which held colonial control over the Congo for over five decades.",
            "answers": ["Belgium"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This American president graduated from Eureka College in Illinois and began his career as a sportcaster in Iowa in 1932. He later served as the President of the Screen Actor's Guild then governor of California. John Hinckley attempted to assassinate this man in during his first term, thinking it would impress the actress Jodie Foster. Name this 40th US President who defeated Jimmy Carter and Walter Mondale.",
            "answers": ["Ronald Reagan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Debuting in 1975, this iconic American television show is known for its live sketch comedy and variety performances. Created by Lorne Michaels, it has launched the careers of many comedians and actors, becoming a staple of weekend television. The show is renowned for its topical humor, parodies of political figures, and musical performances, making it a significant part of American pop culture. It has also won numerous Emmy Awards over the decades. What is the name of this long-running program that features a different celebrity host and musical guest each week?",
            "answers": ["Saturday Night Live"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This Harlem Renaissance poet, who once worked as a busboy, is celebrated for his vibrant depictions of African American life and culture, often incorporating elements of jazz and blues into his writing. Two of his most famous poems include \"I, Too,\" a defiant declaration of racial equality, and \"Harlem,\" a poignant exploration of deferred dreams. He is considered a pioneer of jazz poetry, and his works continue to inspire and resonate with readers today.",
            "answers": ["Langston Hughes"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This vibrant city, nestled between lush mountains and the Atlantic Ocean, is famous for its dramatic landscape, featuring iconic landmarks such as Sugarloaf Mountain and the Christ the Redeemer statue. Its world-renowned Carnival celebrations, filled with music, dance, and elaborate costumes, attract millions of visitors each year. The city's Guanabara Bay, one of the world's largest natural harbors, is dotted with picturesque islands and surrounded by stunning beaches like Copacabana and Ipanema. Which city, the second most populous in Brazil, served as the nation's capital from 1763 to 1960?",
            "answers": ["Rio de Janeiro"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This television show concluded its 25th season on May 16, 2024, extending it's record as the longest-running primetime action series. It airs on NBC and was created by Dick Wolf as a spin off of a classic procedural crime drama. This series focused on two detectives as they investigate and prosecute sexually based crimes in New York City. Name this TV show which stars Mariska Hargitay and Christopher Meloni which was the first spin off from Law and Order. ",
            "answers": [
                "Law and Order: SVU",
                "SVU",
                "special victims unit",
                "law and order: special victims unit"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This organelle, named after its Italian discoverer in 1897, is often referred to as the cell's \"post office\" due to its role in modifying, sorting, and packaging proteins and lipids. It consists of a series of flattened, stacked pouches called cisternae, and plays a crucial role in the secretory pathway. What is the name of this organelle, essential for cellular transport and processing?",
            "answers": ["Golgi Apparatus"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Orphaned as a teenager and captured by the British during the Revolutionary War, this future president survived an assassination attempt in 1835 when his would-be killer's pistols misfired. Nicknamed \"Old Hickory\" for his toughness, he rose from humble beginnings to become a lawyer, planter, and military leader. This seventh U.S. president is remembered for his controversial policies towards Native Americans, including the Indian Removal Act and the Trail of Tears. Who is this prominent figure in American history?",
            "answers": ["Andrew Jackson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This historic city, built on seven hills, straddles the Tiber River in the Lazio region of central Italy. Its strategic location on the river, approximately 15 miles inland from the Tyrrhenian Sea, contributed to its rise as a powerful empire. The city's iconic landmarks, including the Colosseum, the Pantheon, and the Forum, are testaments to its rich history and cultural significance. Which city, often called the \"Eternal City,\" serves as the capital of Italy and the spiritual center of the Catholic Church, with Vatican City located entirely within its boundaries?",
            "answers": ["Rome"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This iconic American actress, model, and singer, born Norma Jeane Mortenson in 1926, became one of the most popular sex symbols of the 1950s and early 1960s. Renowned for her comedic \"blonde bombshell\" roles, she starred in several successful films, including \"Some Like It Hot\" and \"The Seven Year Itch,\" the latter featuring the famous scene of her standing over a subway grate as her white dress is blown upwards. Her life, marked by glamour and personal struggles, ended tragically in 1962. What is the name of this legendary film star known for her beauty and tragic life story?",
            "answers": ["Marilyn Monroe"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This region, notorious for its rugged terrain and dense rainforests, poses a significant challenge to travelers and remains a missing link in the Pan-American Highway. It's a biodiversity hotspot, home to a wide array of flora and fauna, including jaguars, harpy eagles, and poisonous dart frogs. Indigenous groups like the Embera and Wounaan have inhabited the area for centuries. In recent years, it has become an increasingly perilous route for migrants fleeing economic and political instability, seeking passage between South and Central America. What is the name of this 66-mile stretch of undeveloped wilderness between Panama and Colombia?",
            "answers": ["Darien Gap"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Austrian-born corporal and failed artist served in the Bavarian Army during World War I. He rose to power as the charismatic leader of the National Socialist German Workers' Party, becoming Chancellor of Germany in 1933. His hateful ideology, outlined in his book Mein Kampf, led to the persecution and genocide of Jews and other minorities in the Holocaust. His aggressive expansionist policies, including the annexation of Austria and invasion of Poland, plunged the world into the devastating conflict of World War II. Who is this infamous dictator who committed suicide in a Berlin bunker in 1945?",
            "answers": ["Adolf Hitler"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Nicknamed \"Big Red,\" this chestnut racehorse with three white stockings won the Triple Crown in 1973, setting records in all three races that still stand today. His Belmont Stakes victory, a 31-length triumph, is considered one of the greatest performances in horse racing history. Upon his death, his heart was found to be more than twice the size of an average horse's heart, a possible explanation for his exceptional speed and endurance. Name this legendary racehorse.",
            "answers": ["Secretariat"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This openly gay American poet, known for his raw and confessional style, wrote a controversial poem which led to a landmark trial for freedom of speech in 1957. A leading figure of the Beat Generation, he was expelled from Columbia University for writing obscene graffiti and befriended other Beat icons like Jack Kerouac and William S. Burroughs. His works often explored themes of sexuality, spirituality, and the American experience, with notable poems including \"Howl\", \"Kaddish\", and \"America.\"",
            "answers": ["Allen Ginsberg"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Born in Texas and raised in Kansas, this five-star general served as Supreme Commander of the Allied Forces in Europe during World War II, overseeing the D-Day invasion of Normandy. A gifted strategist and charismatic leader, he later became president of Columbia University before returning to public service. Known for his \"Atoms for Peace\" speech and his farewell address warning of the \"military-industrial complex,\" he championed infrastructure development with the Interstate Highway System during his two terms in office. Who is this military hero and 34th President of the United States?",
            "answers": ["Dwight D Eisenhower"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This politician is being investigated by the FBI for possible campaign violations related to illegal fundraising from Turkish nationals. Before he was a politician, this man served as a New York police office for more than 20 years. He went on to become the first Black President of Brooklyn Borough in New York in 2013. In 2021, this man was elected Mayor of New York over Curtis Silwa.",
            "answers": ["Eric Adams"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This exiled revolutionary adopted a pseudonym derived from the Lena River. This man published the \"April Theses\" which led to the October Revolution, in which his Bolsheviks overthrew the Russian regime. An offshoot ideology of Marxism bares his name. Name this man who was the first leader of the Soviet Union from 1922-1924.",
            "answers": ["Vladimir Lenin", "Vladimir Ilyich Ulyanov", "Lenin"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This sprawling metropolis, the third most populous in Africa, traces its roots back to a Roman fortress established in the 1st century AD. Its name, derived from the Arabic word \"Al-Qahirah\" meaning \"the victorious,\" reflects its historical significance as a center of power and culture. Located near the apex of the Nile Delta, it boasts iconic landmarks such as the Citadel of Salah al-Din and the Mosque of Muhammad Ali. Which city, a modern-day megacity with a population exceeding 20 million, is home to the renowned Museum of Egyptian Antiquities, housing a vast collection of ancient artifacts, including the treasures of Tutankhamun?",
            "answers": ["Cairo"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Overcoming polio as a child, this athlete became the first American woman to win three gold medals in track and field at a single Olympic Games. Competing at the 1960 Rome Olympics, she dominated the 100-meter and 200-meter sprints, as well as the 4x100-meter relay, solidifying her place as one of the greatest female athletes of all time. Name this athlete who retired from competition at the peak of her athletic career in 1962 and went on to graduate from Tennessee State University and become an educator and coach.",
            "answers": ["Wilma Rudolph"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This German astronomer, mathematician, and author was born in Weil der Stadt in 1571. Despite suffering from smallpox as a child, he worked as an assistant to Tycho Brahe and later succeeded him as the imperial mathematician. He has been described as the \"father of science fiction\" for his novel Somnium. He is most known for his three laws of planetary motion, which revolutionized our understanding of the solar system and paved the way for Isaac Newton's law of universal gravitation. Who was this key figure in the scientific revolution?",
            "answers": ["Johannes Kepler"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This popular Christmas character, created by Robert L. May for a Montgomery Ward promotional booklet, was initially rejected by the company's executives for his unusual physical trait. Voiced by Billie Mae Richards in the 1964 stop-motion animated television special, this character is ostracized for his unusual nose but eventually becomes a hero when his unique attribute proves essential for guiding Santa's sleigh through a blizzard. The character's story has been adapted into numerous songs, movies, and television shows, and has become a beloved symbol of acceptance and embracing differences.",
            "answers": [
                "Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer",
                "rudolph",
                "rudolf",
                "rudolph the reindeer"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Originally written in French during World War II, this allegorical novella tells the story of a young prince who travels from his asteroid to Earth, encountering various characters like a vain rose, a conceited king, and a drunkard. The book is beloved for its simple yet profound message about the importance of childlike wonder and imagination, and it has been translated into over 500 languages, making it the second most translated book of all time after The Bible. What is the name of this book which has sold over 140 million copies?",
            "answers": ["The Little Prince"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ]
]
